Krish NAik: Hello, everyone. Please let me know, am I audible or not.
Krish NAik: Everyone, please let me know. My setup is a bit different, so, like, please provide the confirmation.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so, let me start. I think this is my desktop 3, okay?
Krish NAik: Hmm, perfect.
Krish NAik: So, this will be our third project that we'll be discussing today. I'm sharing the link.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, you people in the meantime…
Krish NAik: And take a clone of this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, the third project, according to the syllabus that we have, so… if I show…
Krish NAik: So, let me just open Notion also. For a long time, I have not opened Notion.
Krish NAik: Post day of the third project, missed a couple of classes. Alright, you can have a look into that one.
Krish NAik: For the first day of the third week, yesterday is the first day only.
Krish NAik: It's based on last class, so the implementation that I have taken, I've kept it, very, very similar to,
Krish NAik: the last class-based implementation that I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… I think this is the link to the syllabus, yes.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's go through, like, what are the things that are remaining.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, from here, most of the things will be clear.
Krish NAik: So, this is… okay, document parses are done, Lama Index, we have done it. Haystack module is remaining, so after your third pitch, so probably from next week, Sunday.
Krish NAik: Okay, if I do the allotment, so probably, like, this week, next week, after that. So once this project 3 gets completed, we will start with Haystack.
Krish NAik: Haystack, again, like, at the end of the day, it's your choice, I will say. For enterprise-based solutions, Haystack is much more widely used. Okay.
Krish NAik: But again, few implementations are open source field, so… this module will be a small module only, because the main focus in this course will be with respect to Lanshen and Llama.
Krish NAik: Okay, then you have Langra, but before starting Langrav, I want to focus on,
Krish NAik: the graph rag, that will be one. And before graph rag, I think, multimodal rag.
Krish NAik: Okay, so both the things. Then, finally, because Langgraph is only the agentic part, but the same things, if you really look into, like, advanced query techniques, these things we have already gone through.
Krish NAik: Only the metadata extraction part is left. Other than that, hybrid strategies, query enhancement, this also I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, structured data rack is done. Now, I think,
Krish NAik: After your haystack discussion is done, then two main rack types. One is the multimodal rack, and the other one is the graph rag, these two rags that we'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: Because in multimodal, I am thinking about taking a complete image-based dataset.
Krish NAik: Complete image, it means that probably something medical images or something like that. Okay?
Krish NAik: So let's see and let me plan for that.
Krish NAik: But, okay, then, memory for rack, this is a small module only.
Krish NAik: Then, agent take, okay, alright.
Krish NAik: This will come most of the things under Langraph. In production, scaling, EKs, and Farget, when I'll be discussing for your fourth and fifth project, most of. Like, self-rag, we have discussed, CRAG, we have discussed, okay, Adaptive, which is basically a combination.
Krish NAik: Adaptive is yet remaining. I think, probably. When I discuss Langrav, then I can take that…
Krish NAik: Particular implementation. Because, see that self, self is done. After that, we discuss adaptive.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, GraphRag, fine-tuning, so for this RAFT RAFT is there. That particular model will come.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, MCP again, like, I'm not sure, like, I will be taking MCP, or I will ask somebody to take it. MCP is not…
Krish NAik: Such an important one for me.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… majorly it will take around more 2 months that I can see.
Krish NAik: Okay, a rough estimation. Now, your third project, according to the one, so the first one, and the Project 2, in Project 2, I've added a lot of other things, but,
Krish NAik: For now, Project C, I'll be keeping it simple. Okay, so the main thing was hybrid search rag, but here I've included CRAG.
Krish NAik: As well as that self-reg module.
Krish NAik: Okay, and for the ranking also, I have kept both the implementations, an open source one, MS Marco model, and as well as, I have taken a paid, version from Voa H1. Voa Jerry ranking models are also good. Okay, I'm not taking Kohar, later on, Kohar integration, I think, by next week that we can do.
Krish NAik: When we are expecting the last session.
Krish NAik: Take it, like, second week of April, if I say.
Krish NAik: Okay, session-wise. So, discussion-wise, I can do it in April also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Muhammad, that's a rough estimation that I feel like second week of April, most of the things will be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, then multimodal… because for multimodal, really, like, exactly selecting which type of data, so something from computer vision-based data shifts that I'm planning right now.
Krish NAik: Alright, and finally, some will be, like, smart code fix, or code assistant type project for the final one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the third project, which is basically the hybrid search rack.
Krish NAik: And even, like, advanced chunking is simply, like, I've used the Dockling Hybrid chunker, if you remember. Pretty much the same one.
Krish NAik: Hi, Bridge Chandler Dokling.
Krish NAik: The implementation is pretty much the same one.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, just like last time. So, I've not changed anything, because this is a hybrid chunker, and it works really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Other than that, Voj, if you want, you guys can create your account with Voadj, I think.
Krish NAik: Word, right?
Krish NAik: This product is from Mongo. Okay, so Mongo-based guys generally use it. So, if you want, you can use. They have their own embedding models also. For now, my selection is only about the re-ranking one, so you guys can do a…
Krish NAik: login or a sign up here, and you can create your own API key if you want. Okay, again, this part is optional. I have kept an open source solution directly, like the MS Marco model, so if you guys want it, you can do the testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here, you can create an API key. There is a limit, okay? Again, like, it's not like that unlimited times, but I think if you try to hit it 10 to 15 times, there is not a problem for initial testing. Later on, you need to add credits, but for your initial testing, everything will work fine.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's a paid one. Generally, for enterprises, we do use it.
Krish NAik: Okay, similarly, Cover is also there. So, for now, I've taken watch, but any one that can be used.
Krish NAik: The watch re-rank, model even got launched.
Krish NAik: I think, within, like, last 10 days, or last 15 days. So I've taken this one.
Krish NAik: There were no major updates in Kohar.
Krish NAik: But, this is the same thing, we can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody, please let me know once you guys have taken the clone. Yes or no, please let me know. Or should I share it again?
Krish NAik: Where is watch?
Krish NAik: Which watch? Jatin Darabali?
Krish NAik: Okay, joint late altered. Fine.
Krish NAik: I'm doing the environment variable, okay, alright. In the meantime, people who have joined new, okay, so just…
Krish NAik: This time, I have not shared a requirement.txt, so just be sure you are familiar with the setup, otherwise, please, check, this part. If you don't have install UV, if you have, then you can move to the next step.
Krish NAik: So, here I think I have given that particular command also.
Krish NAik: This is leave the test part for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think…
Krish NAik: You can use UV sync, that is the easiest way. Again, the command is UVSYNC, I thought I provided, but…
Krish NAik: Not shared. The other API key that you need is Tabuli for API search, okay? I think everybody knows, and you guys already have the Tabula API key with you. Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because in the last class, I think we have worked with, DuckDo, but, actually in production, it's good to select, like, Tabula is really great.
Krish NAik: Then you have EXA. This is also widely used.
Krish NAik: XR such.
Krish NAik: In enterprise-based applications, these two are the major ones.
Krish NAik: Okay, one is EXA, Best Search API for your AI, and the other one is Tabuli. So, initially, I've integrated Tabuli, so probably later on I can switch it to Excel also.
Krish NAik: These are, again, paid products. You do have limited free searches.
Krish NAik: everyone. Yes, and for your… Tabuli, if I do a login, just wait.
Krish NAik: Continue with Google.
Krish NAik: I think only two major API keys are required, and this is for your C rack, guys. Okay, like, if you look into the key, now, as you know, in your corrective rag, you need a web search fallback, okay? So for that particular condition, this is required. In self-rag, you don't need a web search.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: Here, directly, you can copy this API key, and you can keep it in your… so let me just open my text editor.
Krish NAik: I think…
Krish NAik: env.example. Okay, only keep your main OpenAI API key.
Krish NAik: Okay, and Tavila API key, I think initially two are required, so just wait, I will be sharing my ENV file.
Krish NAik: I think, okay? So if you really check, so…
Krish NAik: One API key that I have is the OpenAI. I think everybody knows that, so this is for our LLM and embedding selection. Then you have the Tabula API key, which I showed right now. Once you do the sign up in Tabula, you will be getting the API key. You can just copy it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and paste it here. Then, re-ranker backend. So, I told you, in my code, there are two different types of re-rankers. One is the local one, using sentent transformers, where I have used MS Marco model.
Krish NAik: Okay? Or if you switch it to Voyage, okay, so that option is there. In my config, I'll be showing you. So, like, if we want to use a VOAG model or a local model. Okay, so for that, this particular selection that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, and for Voad, simply, from here, you can create a new API key. So that's why, all the API keys I am showing you.
Krish NAik: So, I think these are the only three is required. Voag one is totally optional for now, but two things are very important. One is this OpenAI API key and the Tabula API key, because otherwise CRA won't work.
Krish NAik: Okay? So please do the setup and then let me know. You can keep it simple, like, only 3 for now.
Krish NAik: You can skip the fourth one. Otherwise, just be ready later on, we can do the testing with Vuaj also.
Krish NAik: Should we create accounts for this site? Yes, please do a sign-up, at least. Initially, you need to do a sign-up, otherwise how we will get the keys?
Krish NAik: Okay, because few paid products are there.
Krish NAik: For re-ranking, I have taken the open source version, but here…
Krish NAik: Avoa GD ranking, I think 2.5 that I am using here, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, so there are two different types of model, the D-Rank hyphen 2.5. Okay, now, this is a better model, and they have a lightweight version also, DRank 2.5. So, theirs works very good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'll be… I can use any one of them. Okay, and the free version is… I think everybody knows the free version, the MS Marco.
Krish NAik: The ranking model herding face.
Krish NAik: this, even in our last time, I think, in class.
Krish NAik: We have discussed this one, the MS Marco Mini LM V6.
Krish NAik: In our previous class, we have done the discussion regarding this, but we have not used any enterprise models or coherent-based models.
Krish NAik: What about Quadrant? Quadrant nothing. Quadrant a Docker image that we'll be downloading, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Because, my, let me just open my Docker also.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: So I think, for our initial setup, I need the
Krish NAik: file, so let me just open the README file.
Krish NAik: I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there is a command to start the service of Quadrant. Okay, so this service, like, now what will happen? It will just pull the Quadrant image from the Docker Hub.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a quadrant, like, I have taken a Docker-based implementation, you can take any implementation here.
Krish NAik: So, I will just copy this one, and let me just open my… Not anymore.
Krish NAik: the permanence?
Krish NAik: I think… let me just open the item from you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this particular command, I am just pasting it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what I'm telling, that, my Docker container in that will be having that particular vector database quadrant, which will be running. So, through localhost, 6333, I'll be accessing this.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think you guys have already seen multiple Docker implementations for VectorDB, so I think you guys should be familiar by now.
Krish NAik: Now, Mohit Visari is asking, what is quadrant? Like, how can you ask this question?
Krish NAik: In this course right now, Moit, if you have joined today only, you might ask, but I know you have been there. I think, guys, everybody knows about Quadrant. Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because suddenly, if you say, I don't know about Quadrant, guys, it's a vector DB, because I think in your initial starting four classes, I've showed chroma, files, Quadrant, Duviate…
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Any other unique vector DB that I have shown?
Krish NAik: I don't remember, the list is, really long. Milworth, I have shown.
Krish NAik: Okay, even upstash, Redis IBU, similarly, upstash has a vector DB also, that also
Krish NAik: later on, PG vector also that I am planning. Pinecone I have shown here. So, really, different types that I have shown in this course, okay? So, right now, when I do the Docker run, it will, first of all, download the
Krish NAik: image from Docker Hub, and then it will execute. So, locally, I don't have any images, so if you see here, images are blank, okay? So, let me just do the execution from here.
Krish NAik: And just be sure it is running in a separate terminal, okay? Because, for the image, here you can do. And, if you guys are interested in the, quadrant UI,
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you can see, access the web UI at this local host. Okay.
Krish NAik: So, this is the link that they are providing. I think, use system browser.
Krish NAik: Can you see here?
Krish NAik: Okay, previously, it was not there, but, right now, if you really look into, there is no collection. It's just like Millworth, they have upgraded, they are rewind, but, from here, I can do everything, so…
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm just telling you, so later on I'll be showing you once we are creating the collection, okay? But this option is also there.
Krish NAik: So, this is running in a separate terminal, and I will go back to my main code.
Krish NAik: So, I think that I can open it and wrap.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure you guys have done that.
Krish NAik: Quadrant setup.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then source, VNV… In my case, I do have a virtual environment, guys. If you don't have a virtual environment, just be sure you are using UVSync. That is the command.
Krish NAik: Okay? UV space sync.
Krish NAik: I think everybody should be familiar with that particular command, if it is for first time, because in this project, I don't think I have shared a requirement.pht.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in your case, if you don't have a .VENV folder, most of the times you have created it. Okay, so what you can do, you can do a simple UV sync. It will create a new one.
Krish NAik: Okay, only these two are the commands. When you execute everything, by default, like, it will look for that pie project to ML find. Okay, and based on that, it will be creating that.
Krish NAik: Alright, too fast to catch up? Okay, alright, I will wait 5 minutes. Okay, so, not 5 minutes, let's wait 2 minutes, and people,
Krish NAik: Who are doing it for the first time?
Krish NAik: Okay, you can use, like, Please take a clone, and then use the command UVSYNC.
Krish NAik: My idea is that you guys have UV in your system.
Krish NAik: Now, Janika is asking, what is UV?
Krish NAik: You've either… Package manager.
Krish NAik: Guidance.
Krish NAik: Like, UV Package Manager.
Krish NAik: These things I've already discussed in your initial sessions only. UVSync is the command.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have not installed, please do the installation, because I think in this course, more than 60-70% of the students are working with UV.
Krish NAik: Can you please repeat the steps for Quadrant? For Quadrant, please, first of all, start your Docker client. Once your Docker client is up, then directly go to the README file, and here you will see the Docker service, docker run hyphen P.
Krish NAik: Please check the README file. Raja Shekhar.
Krish NAik: Any file which tells UV to install, this is your pyproject.2ml. Here you have all the dependencies.
Krish NAik: Whoever is asking.
Krish NAik: Can we run it from Docker Desktop if the image is available, MS, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, if the image is only not available, then first pull the image, then run the image MS.
Krish NAik: Because right now, this is a much more recent standard.
Krish NAik: That's why. My project, you can test it out, like, if you think should work, please let me know.
Krish NAik: That UVSync is working.
Krish NAik: Because I know everything… will work.
Krish NAik: There should not be any problems.
Krish NAik: So, once you have taken Clone, just a single command, UV sync, and
Krish NAik: Generally in production, when you're using, we use the command using hyphen hyphen, frozen.
Krish NAik: Just to be sure all the packages and everything are exactly the same version.
Krish NAik: Okay, but for now, UVSync is fine.
Krish NAik: So, like, at least go through this documentation if you feel.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, most of the things are available here only, so it makes your life much more easy.
Krish NAik: with respect to projects, I think…
Krish NAik: Managing dependencies, this is, like, if you want to update this particular, pyproject.2ml.
Krish NAik: So generally, what you can do, you can use the command UG add, okay? And whichever package you want to add it. For example, Jupyter, JupyterLab, so automatically, this file will be updated, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so under dependencies, for example, do I have Jupyter here? I'm just showing you that part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want me to UV add…
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I have done that, okay, this file should be updated.
Krish NAik: Just one.
Krish NAik: Can you see here, Jupyter got added here?
Krish NAik: So, similarly, you can do UVA add, UV remove, all those things that can be done.
Krish NAik: So there is a requirement.txt file? I don't think I have shared any requirement.txt, Satish.
Krish NAik: Yes, this time I have shared a PyProject.2ml file.
Krish NAik: What after you've been saying done? Nothing more.
Krish NAik: You rethink.
Krish NAik: means, your virtual environment will be created. If your virtual environment is created, guys, in the next step, you just need to activate that environment.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: We have to install all libraries from PyProject Correct.
Krish NAik: So, like, if you do an ubasing, automatically, it pulls everything from this file.
Krish NAik: I think everybody has done the first setup, like, virtual environment. Once the virtual environment is available, just activate it. That's the bare minimum.
Krish NAik: Now, done UVSync, no need to install. When you do UVSync, it will install the libraries. Satish.
Krish NAik: Instead of setup.setup.py is an old one, like, it's an old standard. Recent projects is much more PyProject.2ml month.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, please let me know. Like, you guys have done the Docker setup. OpenAI API key, I think everybody has it. Tabula API key, you got it for the CRAG? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because if these 3 setups are done, then I can start, actually, like, the workflows folder. There are certain things.
Krish NAik: Okay, done, you've installed. What to do with Quadrant? For Quadrant, you just need to run one command. This one. Done.
Krish NAik: docker run hyphen P. Okay, so first it will pull, and then it will run in localhost, like, 6333 is the port.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please let me know, because…
Krish NAik: Actually, you need OpenAPI key, Tabula API key, and Bare Minimum Docker.
Krish NAik: Once this part is done, let me know.
Krish NAik: In this project, a lot of things, like, high deal also there. I'll be showing you step-by-step, like, what are the things that we have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once you guys have done the configurations, please let me know.
Krish NAik: When I'm telling configurations, it means that in your .env file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure you have these 3, or 4. VOH API key is totally optional, so at least 3 or 4 of these API keys are available with you.
Krish NAik: Okay, then Docker. For Docker, you need that, it should be running. So, I have executed that. I think, here, my Docker is running, quadrant.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… I think only these two things.
Krish NAik: And other than that, nothing is required.
Krish NAik: Packages are installing.
Krish NAik: Okay, I don't think packages should take a lot of time, but you can let me know.
Krish NAik: UV sync is the new command, correct?
Krish NAik: Okay, already. Yes, it will take time, so let's wait 2 to 3 minutes. Actually, the main…
Krish NAik: Problem is, PyTorch.
Krish NAik: And with PyTorch, you have that sentient transformers.
Krish NAik: That is the main one.
Krish NAik: Because of, torch, only it takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: And you can remove Torch, because right now, I have that local, re-ranking model. Okay, to run that model, you need…
Krish NAik: torch backend with Filtrane transformers.
Krish NAik: people, okay, should the quadrant, show in my dashboard running, or just listening from the turn? Should the quadrant show in my dashboard? Yes, like, in your case, also, quadrant will be shown, like, if you try to access it.
Krish NAik: through your, I think, practice.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can directly open this one slash dashboard, localhost 633 slash dashboard, if you want to check the UI. It's optional, but again, it's not required.
Krish NAik: Python 3.14, I have not really tested in 3.14, Matthews, if you want, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Okay? The CVSync works only with PyProject Correct. If you don't have piproject.2ml file, then it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: Since… I mean in the Docker desktop, since we run directly, yes.
Krish NAik: Like, show the potential in my dashboard running. Yes, you can, look into… there should be a container created, so you can see, yeah, it's running.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here you can do, or otherwise you can do a docker ps hyphen A. That also works.
Krish NAik: In whichever way if you want.
Krish NAik: Well, right now, let me just, switch on to my virtual environment. I think most of you have done those things.
Krish NAik: Which I have told.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think your PyTorch should be installed by now. Please provide a confirmation.
Krish NAik: Or is it taking some time?
Krish NAik: Mmm, alright, it's taking some time.
Krish NAik: Taking time. Alright.
Krish NAik: It's a one-time thing later on.
Krish NAik: One time thing, fine, do the setup.
Krish NAik: Because once this is done, then we will start with the workflows, okay? So, first upon…
Krish NAik: I think this is the project architecture, and this file should be available with you. I have pushed it.
Krish NAik: Till now, I've not done any deployment part.
Krish NAik: later on next week, I will be adding the deployment.
Krish NAik: For PyTorch, we need to install separately. For PyTorch, no, no, no, no, you don't need to install separately. Like, I think in your, PyProject.2ml, you will be having that one.
Krish NAik: Just wait. This, sentence transformers.
Krish NAik: Okay, so when you do the installation of sentence transformers, automatically torts will be pulled for that.
Krish NAik: It's not required, you don't need to write, specifically that I need to do the installation of Torch. When you do the installation of sentence transformers, that is the backend default one. So…
Krish NAik: So, once the installation is done, you can see that you will be having a virtual environment, just activate the virtual environment.
Krish NAik: Did not get the latest updates for a firm on GitHub.
Krish NAik: I think in GitHub, I have shared the latest update only.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can see 3 hours ago, 2 hours ago.
Krish NAik: This is the latest update.
Krish NAik: Again, Matthews is telling, have you… Matthews is telling, requirement file is missing, should I… people see.
Krish NAik: I have not shared any requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have shared pyproject.2M, you'll fine.
Krish NAik: If you have this file, and if you have UV in your system, simply what you can do, you can run UV space sync using that command, because this project, because in recent versions, people don't use requirements.
Krish NAik: It is a little bit old standard, it's fine, but it's better to use this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so people, again, please don't ask me how to do that, because I have repeated that. If you have this file, only one command is there, UV space sync.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you have that UV space SYMC,
Krish NAik: it will automatically pick up that 2ML file, and from there, it will get the dependencies. It will create the virtual environment. Everything will be done in one shot.
Krish NAik: This is much more, I will say.
Krish NAik: Let's not forward, I think. We have been using EV for more than one year now.
Krish NAik: Before that, poetry was there.
Krish NAik: But, this is how we will be doing the setup. Okay, and just be sure, once you have done UVSync, you will see the virtual environment will be created. Just activate that environment, and then we can execute the command. And before execute the command, just be sure your Docker is running.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think my Docker is running here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in my local use, this one. So just be sure you have your docker running.
Krish NAik: Then, we can move to the next command, I think. Later on, we will start the application, but before, right now, like, Docker is also not important. Let's start with the project architecture and what are the things that I have done.
Krish NAik: So, please try to complete this setup in the next 2-3 minutes. Then I want to start with the main architecture, what are the, different pipeline tick models, flow, and other things, okay? So, please take 2-3 minutes, and please complete that.
Krish NAik: Melind is asking, I see sentence transformers installed, but on PyTorchS correctly.
Krish NAik: If you're in doing sentence transformers, automatically it will pick up PyTorch. Setup done great, Mac M4, alright, you'll be having… right now, I'm using Mac M1, so it's a bit slow.
Krish NAik: And Kodalisar is telling warning… okay, warning is fine, don't worry. Even in my case, I will get that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and people who are getting any problem, see.
Krish NAik: what is the other solution? And simply, like, if you have this file, if you don't have UV, okay, like, simply, these are the requirements. So you can copy-paste this and create a new requirement.txt file.
Krish NAik: Okay, just be sure that, just keep these things, and if you have that requirement.txt, you can do that old style, pap install-requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just be sure you are removing the double quotes. So here, double quotes and double quotes. If you want to do in the old style.
Krish NAik: Maybe?
Krish NAik: Melind is telling how to get Quadrant API key. I'm not using Quadrant API key. Quadrant is running locally in my Docker container, Rahul. You don't need Quadrant.
Krish NAik: Okay? Okay, ignored that was old, okay, fine. Environment is installed, how to create, so generally what happens, Mitesh, people are asking how to create a project. Alright.
Krish NAik: So let me just open here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just create a folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now I am inside a folder. Now, think about, inside this folder, I want to create a project.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can write something like this, UV, init, and the name of the project.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, for example, the name of the project I want to give it, our C is…
Krish NAik: A rag.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now I'm telling. So, automatically, this folder will be created, and your pyproject.2ml will also be created. So, if I show you UV, init, and then the name of the project.
Krish NAik: Can you see here, it's told that the project got initialized at this particular folder. So, now it's asking to do a CD into that. Okay, if I do a CD, CSRI,
Krish NAik: Okay, and if I do an LS hyphen in…
Krish NAik: Can you see automatically your .git file.gitignore file, then your Python version file, pyproject.2ml file, readme file, everything got created?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the easiest way. Okay, so that's why everything gets created, and later on, inside this, if you want to do any updates, so, like, UV add, UV remove, those things you can do.
Krish NAik: Alright, now please go through the documentation, these 6 I have shown you, okay? Now I'll be deleting this folder.
Krish NAik: Love it.
Krish NAik: Hmm, Arif, my friend Arif.
Krish NAik: What was the name of the folder? Test,
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think by this time…
Krish NAik: For everybody, it should be done. Can we start with… ahead with the project architecture?
Krish NAik: Where is this file of the architecture? I think, I have shared the workflows folder.
Krish NAik: Inside that workflows you have.
Krish NAik: Can you see here? The projectarchitecture.md?
Krish NAik: It might take time, these are all mermaid-based workflows, but… It should be working great.
Krish NAik: Raga's asking this Yuvi, I need to do…
Krish NAik: in the VS Code or outside. Really, like, I'm not using VS Code, so…
Krish NAik: VS Code is not necessary. You can do everything from terminally. It's not related to an ID.
Krish NAik: which one we should, follow… going forward, like, if you're working in enterprise, use PyProject.2M. That is the standard.
Krish NAik: In 2025, I think, before that also, like, before UV, people were using poetry.
Krish NAik: So, like, from there, that pipeproject.2mlconcept thing.
Krish NAik: Any link would you share for references, Apijit?
Krish NAik: Please look into the official documentation, only 4 or 5 commands are there for your main UV setup, like, you do an UV init.
Krish NAik: And if somebody is sharing the pyproject.2ml file, and whenever you will be doing, by default, you will see that one log file will be created.
Krish NAik: Okay, in your case also, just lock file.
Krish NAik: So, this file. And these are the exact wheels for your Python. Which package, which one? Okay, so much more detailed level. So, in production, actually, you can…
Krish NAik: really look into this file, and it becomes much easier. Like, across your entire team, all the dependencies and everything will be exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Rajat is asking, where is the project architecture? It will be inside the workflows folder, no, check this workflows folder.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys. I think we can proceed. We have spent enough time setting up everything.
Krish NAik: 30 minutes.
Krish NAik: on which tool you are creating? I'm using AI, like, generally, GPT.
Krish NAik: models.
Krish NAik: Lakshmi is telling the diagrams are not opening, please use a markdown renderer file.
Krish NAik: Which will help you to do the rendering of Markdown in any IDE.
Krish NAik: I'm using, I think,
Krish NAik: I'm using this one, Markdown Preview Enhanced.
Krish NAik: All right. So guys, I think we can start. Most of you are good to go with this.
Krish NAik: I have not executed the Jatinder, till now the application. Okay, so… just wait. Once we've done the main discussion, then we will start that.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, for that also, there is an extension for 2ML files. I have not done the installation, but you can.
Krish NAik: Use that extension. Then it will be rendered.
Krish NAik: Alik.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, so this is a high-level system architecture that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, again, localhost 8000 slash docs, because I'll be… I'm working with FastAPI, the main user slash API client. Right now, there is no UI that I have separately attached.
Krish NAik: So, this is the main entry point of your application, main.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, you have few routes. Okay, so one is the Compare API, route. Now, this will do the comparison, of your standard RAG, CRAG, and SRAG.
Krish NAik: Okay, so all those rack in a single shot, if you want the comparison for that, this API, is there. Then, two major APIs, one is the upload API and the query API. So, upload means your data ingestion phase, when you upload a document.
Krish NAik: Chunks will be created, then embeddings, and it will be saved inside your Docker container, where Quadrant is running. Okay, so there the collection will be created. So, once you do this particular upload.
Krish NAik: And query is, once you have this, the query will come, then your embedding, like, OpenAI is there, okay, so that your, query will be converted into embeddings, and then your search operation that will take place.
Krish NAik: Now, for our search, we have a hybrid setup, right? A BM25, with your dense and semantic search implementation, that we have.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, local storage uploads, so here, I have a very specific, folder, the local one. Later on, like, when I'm moving to cloud, I can change this, just like in Project 2, we have done S3, like, PDF, MD, all those type of files.
Krish NAik: So, when I'm hitting this particular upload API, so what will come this document processing? Okay, this is the main one where you will be having your main file upload, then comes your dockling hybrid chunker implementation, all those things are inside this particular service.
Krish NAik: Query service is your main retrieval service. Okay, now, there is… we have the vector search, as well as we have the sparse vector search, so that's why the name is vector search. It means parse, parse, tens. Both the vector search services are available under this.
Krish NAik: Now, the retrievable services, now the question comes, what are the options that you want to use? So, here there is an ID. If you want to enable ID, so directly you can do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I have made the parameters, like, true and false, everything.
Krish NAik: Because Heidi generally takes time, so I feel that it's not always optional, so that particular condition.
Krish NAik: So, once you have this retrieval service.
Krish NAik: Then, the other way around, it will hit the vector store for any, query that is coming to perform the main retrieval.
Krish NAik: Now, Heidi, if you are working with Heidi, you know that Heidi will be using some type of LLM, so this particular route is going towards an LLM service.
Krish NAik: Now, the other services for your self-rag, CRAG, again, for everyone needs an LLM, so everything is connected to this LLM service OpenAI wrapper, because in our main project.
Krish NAik: So, every major service. For re-ranking, do you need an LLM? Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Please tell me in the chat quickly.
Krish NAik: for re-ranking.
Krish NAik: People are telling for re-ranking, we need an LLM. No. For re-ranking, why you need an LLM? One is the local one, which is the sentence transformers. The other one is the wage.
Krish NAik: AI API.
Krish NAik: So there is no OpenAI LLM for re-ranker.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, manually, if you say that, okay, please, if you ask an LLM, please do a ranking, you will say in the prompt, okay, these are the chunks, please… then, in that case, you can manually do it, but we are not doing that particular implementation here.
Krish NAik: Okay? So LLM-based SADI ranking, if you want to do, then in that case, we need. But in our current implementation, we don't need that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so your ID needs the LLM service, your SRAC, and as well as your CRAC.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, with CRAG, you have a web search, so that's why you can see here the web search service with the Tablei client that I have, and this is an external service, so that's why you need the Tablei search API to perform any type of web searches.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Rajat is filling in Rahagas, can you use Olama?
Krish NAik: Like, Raga is a framework.
Krish NAik: Okay, in Ragas, okay, for, yes, if you want that, LLM selection for Ulama, if you're asking, yes, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Even for your embedding model, that is also open source, you can pick up. Like, Gemma 300 million, that is a good one. Tajit.
Krish NAik: Okay, shouldn't we have logging and evaluation? So, right now, logging, again, it's not a compulsory one, Muddhasar. See, I have my main logging module, I think I have used log group. Evaluations I have not added very specifically.
Krish NAik: Because whenever you are doing, like, self-rag, CRAG, the main purpose is one will make your retriever much more better, which is CRAG, the SRAG out there, which will make your…
Krish NAik: Finally, LLM-generated output much better. So, I have not done that, but again, I can integrate RAGAS here just, for evaluation purpose.
Krish NAik: Okay, right now it's not integrated.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, then my CRAG, SRAG, okay, so these two things. Okay, vector store, this is my main OpenAI API with LLM. External services, this is my quadrant running in my local machine docker.
Krish NAik: Tavila API key, again, this is for my web search, and Voyage API, this is, again, optional, so that's why this is a dotted line. If I'm selecting Voyage from my config, then only it will be picked up. Otherwise, simply this particular entire node will be skipped.
Krish NAik: MS is asking which Markdown to… use Markdown Preview. There are many markdown, extensions. I'm using the HTML Markdown Preview.
Krish NAik: Okay, so these are the core components that I have. Now, for each service, you will be having a file. So if I show you, if you go inside app, mean.py, this is the mean starting point of our application. Okay, and then inside my API, I have these two routes, the query route and the upload route.
Krish NAik: Then my core services is this retrieval.py.
Krish NAik: Then comes your, services. So here I have my CRAG, then you have document processing using Docklins, embedding service.
Krish NAik: Then, IDE, LLM service, re-ranking, self-reflective, vector store, and Web Search.
Krish NAik: Okay, so majorly, all those core modules implementation that I have, I have kept it. And inside your re-ranking, you have both the options, the local one. Okay, so later on, I'll be discussing the code, but for now, the major services which are there, and everything is listed here.
Krish NAik: Okay, hold it.
Krish NAik: Now, few, service, or few main classes that I'll be using. Okay, now this is the main service layer, okay, and these are the data models. So, what are data models? I think everybody knows about PyTentic.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: In Pyntic, you create your custom models.
Krish NAik: like, response models, query models, okay? So, like, first of all, let's talk about the service architecture, then I will come to the data models.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, my,
Krish NAik: So one is the self-reflective service.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the core implementation of mine, SRID.
Krish NAik: Okay, then in our re-ranking service, my… I have two implementations. One is the local one, one is the watch one. And the main purpose of this re-ranking is to take your query, take the chums, and then top K. So here, I think, by default, my top K number in re-ranking is 20 that I have selected.
Krish NAik: Are you going to have sparse vector? Yes, that is by default in your hybrid search.
Krish NAik: Okay, in your hybrid search, I think you have that particular implementation.
Krish NAik: So, if I… you can just look into the main file, people who are asking about that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… services from here.
Krish NAik: Once you start, to look, Majorly will be getting all of your search-based results.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, my one is SRAG implementation for SRAG. Okay, so generating the initial answer, the query, and the chance. Reflect on answer, that module is there. Okay, then execute self-reflective rag, here, like, multiple iterations that will be going on.
Krish NAik: And if query refinement is required, which is the refined query. Okay, so here, I think, 3 times I was…
Krish NAik: max 3 times that I have given. If within 3 times if it fails, simply it will say that
Krish NAik: Okay, like, the document or the available chunk was not available, okay?
Krish NAik: And if it is not available, then CRAG automatically that web search fall condition that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'll be showing you that, don't worry. Now, re-ranking already told CRAC, again, like, first of all, you will be evaluating your, relevance for query to chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, based on that, you will be doing these executions? Okay. Don't worry, see, I have a dedicated Markdown file just to explain the CRAG implementation that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for now,
Krish NAik: you can think about, I will tell you the exact, implementation labels. So, just focus on the high-level project architecture right now.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, then you have your main web search service. Again, for this, inside my services, I have a dedicated file to call the tabulae API key whenever I need a web search functionality. Then comes the retriever service. Now, inside this retriever service, again, like, the vector stored service that I'll be calling.
Krish NAik: Your embedding service that I'll be calling, and ID service, which is an optional
Krish NAik: By default, if we want, then only we can do it. And for Heidi, the max number of generations, that hypothetical document generation, 3 generations are there.
Krish NAik: Not… because if you try to generate more and more documents, it will take more and more time.
Krish NAik: LLM service, this is from OpenAI. Then I have the, document processor. Here, I told I'm using the hybrid chunker. Okay, and this is where your vector store, your search, absort, okay, these two major.
Krish NAik: I think one is your main search, so your hybrid search implementation. Upsearch means uploading your chunks there.
Krish NAik: Delete, if you want to delete any source file with that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and one is ensure collection. Ensure collection means whenever our application starts, we always have a check that the collection is available or not.
Krish NAik: Inside my Docker container. So, if your Docker container is not running, simply it will throw the error.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why that ensure collection is there.
Krish NAik: Now, some pydentic models, and these models are very, very important whenever you get any type of validation error. Okay, now, this can be because of these type of models that I have defined.
Krish NAik: Okay, and all these models are in which file? These are in models.py. So here you can look into, for every model, like, what is the structure that I have given.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, simply, if you want, you can have a look. But for now, for my query model, I have passed, okay, your actual query. Now, these are the different type of modes in my application. One is standard. Standard means the simple ride.
Krish NAik: Okay, CRAG means only CRAG. Then comes your self-reflective RAG means only self-reflective RAG. And finally comes both. Both means the, implementation of CRAG plus, self-reflective RAG.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in my main parameter, I have total 4 approaches. Again, I am repeating this. This mode is important.
Krish NAik: In this mode, we take four parameters. One is the standard. Standard means the default one. There is no CRAG, no SRAG, okay? Then once, I have only for CRAG-based implementation, one I have for self-rag.
Krish NAik: self-reflective RAG implementation, and both is basically the combination of CRAG and self-reflective rack.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Tonil is asking, can you see? Yes, Asunil, I can see your messages.
Krish NAik: I want to illuminate her feelings.
Krish NAik: Huh, okay.
Krish NAik: Eliminate, yes. So for that, I have the CRAC part, no?
Krish NAik: Hallucination detection, generally, majorly for retrieval level quality that you were asking, Sunil, that's why that CRAC part that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'll be… showing you that main architecture file, then I'll be talking about it.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is my main query one. Okay, so you can test it. This is the same structure that you can get it in your,
Krish NAik: API key. Okay, now this is my main fast API, when I'll be calling my slash query route.
Krish NAik: Then this is the query response. Okay, so here, your actual query, then comes your answer, then what type of mode that I have passed.
Krish NAik: These are the source lists, then comes your CRAC details, then comes your deflection details. Okay, now these things I'll be showing you, because right now, discussing these things doesn't matter. And you can see at every point of time, I'm keeping these two parameters.
Krish NAik: enable ID is equal to false, and enable reranking. Both the operation takes more time. If you want, you can do the testing, but by default, I'm keeping them as false.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, for your query response.
Krish NAik: you have two options, like, if you want to select the CRAC result, exactly what is the return type of your CRAC, and for your SRAG results.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: One important thing, okay? So, if you see here, with my CRAG, I have, this, thing connected. One is the retrieve chunk and the chunk metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, you have to think about the scenario.
Krish NAik: whenever you are working with CRAT, okay, and if I'm telling, okay, that, okay, it will show you the web search best result, it's fine.
Krish NAik: But when you actually, try to do the integration of CRAG with your SRAC, okay, it means that the output of CRAG will be going to SRAG.
Krish NAik: Okay, then you need, actually, to handle your… that web search information as chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I've connected that, your web search results also, I convert them into a structured chunk metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this part is important. If you're not doing any double integration, it's fine, but if you are doing that integration of both CRAG and SRAC, then you need to handle that chunk metadata, okay, because that web search results actually becomes your new chunk.
Krish NAik: I'll think.
Krish NAik: Fine, CRAG result, self-reflective result, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, here you can see hallucination detection for yourself, reflective. So, whether the hallucination detection, this condition is a Boolean, it will simply say, so that's why I've kept it here. Then comes your CRAG evaluation, so I have, again, passed a scoring mechanism, like 0.7, 0.4. Don't worry, all these things are there in that architecture file.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are high-level Pydentic models that I'm using.
Krish NAik: Whenever you get a validation error, it means that this is something related to this models.vy file only.
Krish NAik: Now, your main configuration.env, and this is my Pydantic settings. Now, this is your config.py. So, when you look into config.py, so let me just show you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, what are the important things that I have?
Krish NAik: So, when you look into this file, the same things are there in that also. Okay, you have the main OpenAI API key and the Tabula API key. These two I told, very, very important. Then, where is your vector DB running? It's in local, Docker container, so that's why I passed this, local 0633333.
Krish NAik: Then, Quadrant API key, none, none, because this is running locally. Later on, if I switch to a cloud-based.
Krish NAik: Okay, then two things will come. The cloud URL, the endpoint, okay, and the API key. But right now, I… you can easily switch to a cloud-based implementation also. Okay, so that's why both the options, we have kept it.
Krish NAik: Then my embedding model takes the embedding 3 small LLM model, GPT-4O Mini.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then, okay, few settings with respect to CRAG. What is the relevance threshold? What is the ambiguous threshold?
Krish NAik: Okay, now, don't worry about this, threshold settings, I'll be showing you, okay, when I'll be opening that particular implementation file. Then for self-reflective, also, I do have some settings.
Krish NAik: Retrieval top K, by default, I am selecting top K. Now, this is the return type of your retrieval, whenever you are performing a vector search on top of your vector DB.
Krish NAik: Now, ID, number of hypotheses, I told, I have selected 3. If you go with 5 or 7, it will take more time. Okay, and by default, Heidi enabled by default, which is always false. Okay, so manually, if you make it true, then always it will be enabled. But every time I don't need that.
Krish NAik: Then comes your re-ranking here, so this is my local model. Okay, and right now, my re-ranking is taking the top 20. So, initially, my top K results are 5, so, like, I can reduce it to only 3 for now. Okay, if this will be 50, then 20 will be much better.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, actually this is a bad practice. If I switch it to only 3 for now, this will be much better.
Krish NAik: Because in production, we work with higher numbers, so this will be 50, and this can be 20 or 25, something like that. Okay, so right now, I'm just reducing it, so you guys also be sure you are reducing it.
Krish NAik: Then, re-ranking by default, again, I have kept it false.
Krish NAik: Okay, and re-ranking backend. So, exactly, like, two re-rankers, I have the local one and the Voyage one. So, by default, I'm setting it to local. I'm not using VOAG for now. If you're working with VOAG, you need to pass your VOAG API key, and exactly which model. So, here you can see, I passed re-rank 2.5.
Krish NAik: Then comes your upload directory. Okay, so where all of your documents will be uploaded. If you are working with FastAPI, you will see this uploads folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, and unique ID, UUID, will be generated for each type of file.
Krish NAik: So, when you try that, you will see that automatically it will be coming inside this folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, and we are keeping all these settings into the cache.
Krish NAik: So that's why the most simplest level LRUCH, because this is just application-level catcher that I am doing it. Okay, so now all these settings are available, similarly in this project architecture.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, everything that I have discussed, your core configurations are all available here in the main configuration flow, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just make it a bit smaller, yes.
Krish NAik: I think, Jatindar, why do we have a re-ranker model when we said we did not need a LLM year?
Krish NAik: The re-ranker model is a different thing, LLM is a different thing.
Krish NAik: I have not done the implementation of LLM-based re-ranking.
Krish NAik: I've taken the implementation of using a direct cross-encoder model from Hugging Face, and the other option, I've kept it as a VOAD re-ranking model.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Please use an extension, Satish. I showed you enhanced Markdown Preview with my extension. Also, its core for CRAG plus self-rag does… it's not, an exact adaptive RAG implementation, because when we try to do the
Krish NAik: Actual implementation of Booth, it's an adaptive rag route, but it's not pure adaptive rack.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Does it check the hallucin… hallucination detection? By default, SRAC does it for you. Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, Voyage is a re-ranker model, yes, in Voyage, you have embedding model, re-ranking model, okay? So… I showed these things, no, in class already.
Krish NAik: Then, again, people are asking the same thing, so I think Voach, re-ranking, yes. These are the two available models, re-rank 2.5 and re-rank 2.5 Lite.
Krish NAik: Then you have text embedding models also.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so VOAD4Large, then you have multimodal embeddings, contextualized chunk embeddings, okay, different types…
Krish NAik: Of embedding models which are available.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, I think the configuration flow is… Pretty much easy to understand.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, external dependencies, what are the major external dependencies that I have is the Tableau Search API, Wohaj API, okay? And then your quadrant, which is another external one, and then OpenAI API, okay? So, all these things are pretty much required, but again, this is a totally optional settings that we have.
Krish NAik: Any one we can use it, it's not necessary. Like, most of the times we'll be working with RRF only.
Krish NAik: montage.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, alright, then deployment, leave with the deployment, because right now we have not worked.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, as you can see, these are some performance optimizations, because really, like, I have not done enough optimizations on this one.
Krish NAik: Because if I start doing optimizations, the amount of source code will increase, okay? So, I've kept things. Later on, if you want, you can do it. Because majorly, I don't think the entire application is synchronous, not asynchronous.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, huh… One is that Heidi here cause that goes around.
Krish NAik: Then vector search, again, more chunks, better coverage, but slower processing. Then comes re-ranking local versus API-based implementation, whichever you want.
Krish NAik: Now, all this catch implementation is not there in this project, but again, the same implementation, just like Project 2, you can do it. For your CRAG, SRAG, all those implementations.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your LLM generation, or the model selection. Right now, I think I'm working with Javiter 4.0 Mini, whereas, like, 4O is much costlier. And I think 4.0 is also getting duplicated. Like, I received the mail from OpenAI, I think within next week, it will be deprecated.
Krish NAik: Okay, 31st March is the last date, yes, I think I got the mail for that.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, in our application, everything is synchronous, so nothing is async, okay? Later on, you can simply switch to async.
Krish NAik: the implementation is easier. Pydantic for every type of data validation. Okay, then, my main service initializations, one is the retrieval service, CRAC service.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the other one is SRAG, which is an optional one. Metadata standardization, I have made the metadata to a certain level, but again, not everything I have standardized it. Because I do have the chunk metadata.
Krish NAik: Pydantec model. In that, I have kept it
Krish NAik: But, again, like, it's not really enriched version of the metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, because other things also that we can, like… Alright.
Krish NAik: we can make it much better, okay? And for making your metadata much better, I think later on.
Krish NAik: I don't know how many of you know about the land.
Krish NAik: Extract.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is one live data through which you can create, like, really good metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is really a good one.
Krish NAik: Creating, like, structured metadata from your unstructured documents, this is one way. You can use good NER-based models. The main purpose is NER, and LangExtract helps you. The other one is from Pastino Labs, GlinarV2.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is also really a good one.
Krish NAik: They have, recently launched a new model. Okay, so using this particular model also for metadata extraction, it's really good. Okay, and the same thing happens. You need a good NER, a named entity recognition at any point of time.
Krish NAik: Okay. Later on, I'll be showing you for metadata entrancement, probably one of them.
Krish NAik: Glowage is just a provider, and nothing more.
Krish NAik: CRAG, evaluatable in both modes, okay? Alright, now, error handling, okay?
Krish NAik: Till now, I have not added any monitoring later on.
Krish NAik: Let's see, like, this time what to use. We have already worked with OPEC, we have already worked with, Landsmith this time.
Krish NAik: Let's switch to something, different, like LangFuse or something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so major metrics that we'll be looking into that. Security condition, okay, now these are the default ones. Now, a few other implementations that can be done in future that I have kept it, okay? If you guys want
Krish NAik: to do the implementation, you can erase PRs to me, okay? Take a fork of mine, and then start looking.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is your main high-level project architecture. Now, I'll be talking about, the next one.
Krish NAik: Let's start with our, a CRAC, first of all.
Krish NAik: Yes, Gleaner V2 swung.
Krish NAik: Those are really good for name. Otherwise, I've seen using people's PC also.
Krish NAik: Spacey model is also a good one right now.
Krish NAik: per entity, classification.
Krish NAik: Prior to it, you shared… one is Lang extract, one is Liner V2, one is Spacey. These three are the options for your metadata enrichment.
Krish NAik: Now, Subhas is asking, instead of pulling Quadrant to Docker and use, can we implement a similar approach? Did…
Krish NAik: Okay, you can use that cloud version, Savash. In my code, those settings are there, whichever way you want it.
Krish NAik: If you want to use Cloud, yes, you can create a new… those things that you can do so much. There is no restriction.
Krish NAik: Because in the code, you can just need to update that,
Krish NAik: Fine. So, pass it as an environment variable, I think it will be good.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's talk about the, CRAG mode workflow, okay? Because I have total 4 different type of modes, okay, in my query, whenever I'm performing a query, it'll be passing 4 major modes. One mode is the standard mode, CRAG mode, SRAG mode, and the
Krish NAik: Both mode. Both means both are enabled, CRAG and SRAG.
Krish NAik: MS is asking what is the difference between using Cloud and Docker image? Cloud means one is, like, in your cloud.
Krish NAik: Docker image means it will be running in your local
Krish NAik: In cloud, it is pretty much persistent in Docker. If you delete the Docker container, so everything is deleted in this. As simple as that.
Krish NAik: Anitu, the metadata extracted, is from chunks, exactly correct? Where exactly these chunk extractors comes into the picture. Chunk extractor, like, when you do the implementation, you'll be having a very specific class, Anitu, and that class, you'll be applying on top of those chunks. If you want to look into that.
Krish NAik: People, if you want to have a look into metadata.
Krish NAik: You can look into this particular repo, I think.
Krish NAik: That's what time.
Krish NAik: Alright, thank God.
Krish NAik: This is the one metadata every day.
Krish NAik: Here, I've used Gleaner V2.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you, want to have it checked, you can check this one.
Krish NAik: Look at the metadata hybrid, right? So here, I have used GleanerV2 very specifically.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… I think in the services or somewhere. Here's this metadata extractor class that you have.
Krish NAik: So, there I have passed, like, what are the different type of entities and other things, okay? So, people who are interested, you can have a look.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's get back to our main discussion of the project.
Krish NAik: Now, CRAG mode workflow, the corrective rag, this is the one. Now, here in the workflow diagram, user query will come, retrieve the top K chunks from the vector store. Okay, now, once the chunks are available.
Krish NAik: for every chunk, you need to perform a scoring mechanism, so that's why that relevant score. And here, the parameters that we have passed is 0.7, 0.4 to 0.7, and anything less than 0.4. Okay, so these are the manual scores that we have set.
Krish NAik: So here, relevant score, if it is irrelevant, use retrieve Documents Only.
Krish NAik: Okay, so build the context, retrieve documents, LLM generate answer. If it's 0.4 to 0.7, retrieve plus web search, which is augmentation.
Krish NAik: Okay, I hope everybody understands why I've written augmentation here, because those will be augmented chunks.
Krish NAik: What is the difference between a normal chunk and an augmented chunk?
Krish NAik: In augmented chunk, you have the web search-based results.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear? Yes, you can change the threshold, MS.
Krish NAik: anything, because these are hard-coded parameters directly that I have kept it. Okay, so, like, you can check your config.py. People, please, check the config.py, there you'll be having all those configurations.
Krish NAik: config.py.
Krish NAik: Can you see here? Relevance, ambiguous threshold by default, too.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, MS is asking, and how we are getting the relevant score?
Krish NAik: How will you be getting?
Krish NAik: Through an LLM only?
Krish NAik: Please look into the system architecture. For SRAG and CDRAG in both the places we work with LLMs.
Krish NAik: Okay, now Nitesh is asking, web search on any site, or we can fix any particular website.
Krish NAik: web search is a service, so don't think about on any site. So, like, web search happens, for example, if you use Tabuli, Tabuli will be hitting, like, top 10 or the top 20 web search results. From there, the content will be picked up from those UR.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first, actually, what happens, like, fetch.
Krish NAik: Okay, fetch the URLs. Once the URLs are available, then from there you extract the content from those URLs. EXA can also be used.
Krish NAik: See, guys, use Xi, use Tabula, use Brave, use Dr.co, use Google's SERP API, use anything. The main thing is web search. It's totally up to you which, service that you want to use for web search, okay? In my case, I have taken, this Tabula.
Krish NAik: Alright, now building the final context, documents plus web results, then finally generating the answer. Okay, and these implementations in the last class we have already gone through, okay? And if something is really less than 0.4, by default, it will be the…
Krish NAik: Tableau search only. Okay, and from this web search, you need to build up the context.
Krish NAik: Good.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, then in the next step, okay, so your main retrieval LLM-based.
Krish NAik: Relevance, evaluation, okay, now these are the main JSON responses that you'll be getting, okay, based on your chunks. So, evaluate the retrieved documents, means your chunks from your vector TB against your query. So, you'll be getting all these responses.
Krish NAik: Okay? Whenever you are selecting, this particular implementation. I'm sure you will raise your hand, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because, in the last class, we already discussed that particular notebook. Okay, now these are the main thresholds, okay, which we have passed it inside my.tv env, so based on that, you can pass it. These are the main routing logic, web search integration, okay, the main context assembly that I have.
Krish NAik: two things, I think. Majorly, these are only the things. Other than that, there is nothing there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, if I, just switch on my application, because let's test this mode.
Krish NAik: I think testing is also important.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Should I do the testing later on? Or should I test it now? Let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I will discuss the other moods also, and then only later on. Okay, people are telling later, later, later. Okay, fine.
Krish NAik: Then, after your CRAG, then you have your,
Krish NAik: config, okay, then I have my… Self-reflective mode, alright.
Krish NAik: All right, now, the self-reflective, mood workflow. Okay, so user query, retrieve topK chunks. Okay, now this is pure SRAG implementation, okay, not the combination of both.
Krish NAik: So, once you'll be having correct chunks is equal to retrieve chunks, then you have your max saturation count, where basically it will look for, generate the answers from the current chunk, okay, then comes your mean answer grounding.
Krish NAik: Based on your chums, whether the answer is grounded or not, and this is the written type of that
Krish NAik: Srat, like, whether the answer is grounded, whether there is a hallucination detected, your… the reflection score, the sources cited, okay, if anything that needs to be regenerated. Okay, the… based on the reflection score, we'll be taking both the routing pass, yes or no.
Krish NAik: If it is yes, answer is approved. If it is no, near generation, and retries. Okay, and the maximum number of retries, I've kept it, I think 3 for now. Because it will really take more time if you actually pass 10 or 20. So, bare minimum, 3 that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once the final answer is approved in this case, then directly it will be returned to you. Okay, but if regeneration happens into the picture.
Krish NAik: Then what will? So, return the correct answer despite the low score. Okay, now, if all of your trials are, passed only in that particular condition.
Krish NAik: If, you are getting a much more refined, query built on the reflection feedback. Then again, retrieve new chunks with refined query, update the current chunks here, okay, and again, the same step will proceed ahead.
Krish NAik: Now, this is same implementation, just like in last class we have done. So, with respect to the core understanding, nothing has changed. Pretty much, same implementation.
Krish NAik: One new implementation that I have done, and which is much more interesting, which is basically the combination of Syriac and SRAG.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this implementation is just like last time we have done it in the notebook. I picked up pretty much the same implementation here.
Krish NAik: Yes, the LLM will refine the question exactly correct.
Krish NAik: LLM will define the question. And once the question is defined, based on that, the new chunks that will be retrieved.
Krish NAik: Suvaz is telling, in Sigrat, suppose I do not want to implement web search. Can I say to use a different, yes.
Krish NAik: That you can do. It means that your retriever is different. You don't want to use a web search-based retriever, probably some other retriever technique. Yes, that you can do. Because according to the original paper, they have told web search.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… but you can change it always. It's not like that it is fixed.
Krish NAik: then you won't say exactly C rate.
Krish NAik: Okay, see that means websites to us. That is the only thing.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now… I think… Okay, now, this is the both mode that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, hmm…
Krish NAik: I'll rewrite the query. Okay, now, rewrite the query means, query transformation task data and generate a new context if relevant score is low. Yes, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Wow.
Krish NAik: Because rewrite the query, that is fine, there is no issue in that. And generate a new context. And generate a new context means, actually, like,
Krish NAik: Based on the query, you'll be looking for new chunks, I think. If you, refer that a new context, Subhal, then you are correct.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, unsure about the company project, alright, I will be looking.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine. Guys, now let's try to, look into this particular implementation, okay? So here, like, both mode that I've kept it. Okay, now both mode will do the combination of CRAG as well as SRAG.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, let's try to understand, like, the one thing is, from CRAG, we can take the good thing, which is web search. Okay, and then from, self-rag, so here, pretty much, like, we can look for hallucinations and answer grounding.
Krish NAik: So, that's one of the metrics that comes, if you remember, answer relevancy. That also plays a crucial role here.
Krish NAik: So, in Ragas, if you're actually using it, you can pick up those type of metrics.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, let's focus on the workflow right now. Workflow diagram, here you have the user query, top K chunks from the vector store, then comes your CRAT, and can I say that this particular routing is pretty much the same?
Krish NAik: See, whenever you are executing, CRAG will come first, and then SRAG, yes or no.
Krish NAik: I think this idea everybody should have, according to our last class discussion.
Krish NAik: Yes, CRAG is for Retrieval Level Quality, increase.
Krish NAik: Okay, and whereas SRAG is for your final one, and even SRAG has an added benefit that on-demand
Krish NAik: Retrieval. Okay, it means that whether in one shot you want to, you want to activate your retrieval process or not. Okay, so first of all, in your both mode, your CRAC will come into the picture. And the CRAC implementation is just like last time.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if you really look into CRAG, if relevant, okay, this is fine. Now, this output becomes the input for your self-reflective wrap that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Okay? Similarly, for your CRAG one, if it is ambigious, then comes your augmented chunks, actually. Okay? And that particular chunk needs to be converted into your chunk,
Krish NAik: metadata identical model format, so because of that, I have taken that conversion approach here.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then, if it is irrelevant, then totally it will be under the web search category. Now, whichever way it becomes the input, it means that the output of your CRAT becomes the input for your SRAT here.
Krish NAik: Now, here, again, the SR iteration, less than, max retries, again, 3 retries that I do.
Krish NAik: Generate the answer from working chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay? Then the LLM reflection step will happen, check the grounding, and if the reflection score is… like, I've taken much more, 0.8, okay, so you can keep it 0.5… 0.75, sorry.
Krish NAik: Now, based on that, okay, if it's, like, yes, if it's more than that, the answer is approved. If it's less, needs regeneration. Okay, and retries left. So, maximum retries I've given is 3. So, the same step, okay, if no regeneration is required, returns the correct answer.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if, yes, regeneration is required, refine the query based on the reflection feedback. Okay, and now, entire CRAG will be invoked.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: Entire CRAG will be invoked, because that entire process will come into the picture again. So, if this particular thing fails, because you need to update the working channels.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, you can keep this, that's why I've written this one as CRAC, our re-retrable, because again, the retrieval process will start from the vector store, then, again, we will run the CRAC evaluation, and then trigger the web search if required. So pretty much a repeated stuff.
Krish NAik: That we'll be doing. But, finally, like, I can say this is not exactly an adaptive retrieval implementation, but at least close to adaptive retrieval implementation.
Krish NAik: Now, is this feasible during a query being made, as this will take… yes, see, these type of things, whenever actually we're doing any implementation, with agenting mode and everywhere.
Krish NAik: More things you add, more will be the time.
Krish NAik: That's why I've kept, by default, ID. If you do high D, if you introduce the re-ranking, everything will take time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, if you try to enable all the features, for sure it might take 1 minute.
Krish NAik: Also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes… Everything has a direct impact on your latency.
Krish NAik: Okay, I hope you get that. So, you are correct, Mundo, sir. Yes, these things will take… your latency will increase.
Krish NAik: Also, cost will increase, yes, for sure, because for the internal LLM call that you are actually making for everything.
Krish NAik: Yes, more LLM calls are coming into the picture.
Krish NAik: How do we minimize the latency only by catching? See, generally, I cannot directly say that, Dig Vijay. Yes, now, like, 5-10% that you can do at catching level.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, chain needs to grow with respect to time. Then I can say that, yes, the… but initially the calls will be made.
Krish NAik: No. So, that's why I feel that catching is not a good solution, only 5% reduction with respect to cost, or 10%, but it's not a foolproof solution.
Krish NAik: With respect to time, as your catch increases and increases, so in that way you can do it.
Krish NAik: Now, CRAG has higher chances of hallucination.
Krish NAik: not necessary, like, every time Sirak… I won't say Anirud this one.
Krish NAik: Like, higher chances of hallucination.
Krish NAik: Because you are actually evaluating the quality of the chunk.
Krish NAik: So I feel that… Lesser…
Krish NAik: See, when you try to introduce Anirud, see, hallucination, I will think from LLM generation point.
Krish NAik: Lesser from retrieval point.
Krish NAik: Okay, Anirut, whenever LLM is doing the generation, it's better to do an hallucination check in that step, which is the retrieval step, always remember that.
Krish NAik: In text-to-SQL, it will reduce time caching, yes, for sure. Like, in text-to-SQL, it's fine.
Krish NAik: Wow.
Krish NAik: what else can be, reducing the latency? Like, you should have certain type of conditional checks. Like, when should you perform a query transformation? When should you do a highly…
Krish NAik: Okay, like, all those things, it means that it has to be based on certain type of logic. It's not like that you should enable everything in one shot.
Krish NAik: Okay, because sometimes you just think about, in the query, if somebody passed a single character.
Krish NAik: Nothing will work, neither rag. It means that you have to ask the question again. Please reframe your…
Krish NAik: query.
Krish NAik: Okay, so those type of things also that you need to handle. What else, okay? Based on latency, you need to just check, like, what things. I feel that CRAC implementation is required much more, because if somebody asks you, state-of-the-art right now, immediately.
Krish NAik: Okay, that information LLM won't have. So, a web search tool is a very common tool.
Krish NAik: Okay, every LLM has an agent, and that agent is using this particular tool, so I feel that everyone should use some type of web search tool.
Krish NAik: SRAC, will it have more, chance than to have always SRAG again? SRAG much more from the…
Krish NAik: Llm generate output IPL.
Krish NAik: SRAC plays a crucial role, whereas CRAC from retrieval Level Quality, Mitesh.
Krish NAik: Rajat, as we search data from caching, okay, that is finally, because in caching also, like, you have the same cache, semantic level caching.
Krish NAik: I don't know, like, I have not discussed at semantic level, Kache, but… Anybody else worked with…
Krish NAik: This one, GPT Catcher?
Krish NAik: Yes, this particular library.
Krish NAik: Pape install GPT catcher, you can actually do the setup, it's pretty much easy.
Krish NAik: Because going forward, you need to upgrade your catching system also. Like, initially you can start with, normal catching, but the idea is to move into a semantic-based catching machine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can look into this particular project, and this is from Milverse, this release thing, okay? So this is a good one.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: What is the max threshold we should give for response time? Max threshold, it should be within 1, 2, 3 minutes.
Krish NAik: Generally, see, I feel that to a certain extent,
Krish NAik: some optimization that can be done in your vector DV level.
Krish NAik: But LLM-level things, again, like, you can't use really good models, you have to use some faster response-based models, like flash models, mini models, those type of models are much better.
Krish NAik: Because you need to check all of your response time.
Krish NAik: And, again, like, see, everything, ID will take time. R-ranking will take time, and re-ranking actually takes more time, I feel.
Krish NAik: So, re-ranking should be totally an optional one. If you really feel that you need to implement re-ranking, then only.
Krish NAik: R-ranking takes a very, very…
Krish NAik: long time, as compared to other operations. Like, high D, I feel like you can always use it.
Krish NAik: But re-ranking, I don't feel that every time you should work with it or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's see, I'm… till now, I have not added any query transformation, because Heidi, I take it as one type of query transformation technique only. Okay, but there are other labels of query transformation in the last week we have gone through. I've not implemented those, only Heidi for now.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, I think majorly most of the things we have discussed, now I will start.
Krish NAik: The application, and let me see whether everything is working or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait… here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: docker PS hyphen A. I can see my quadrant is running fine.
Krish NAik: Can you use Llama locally or offline? Yes, for sure, you can work with…
Krish NAik: Ulama, okay, a lot of… locally hosting the models.
Krish NAik: Lower dimension, will lower the cost for sure, Mahmat. Like, 1536, majorly, I've been working with, but I feel that 786 is a good one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… it's much better to work with that, even for your sparse embeddings also, you can decrease that.
Krish NAik: It depends upon use case to use case. There is no fixed time, or the max response time, because people, if they are much more looking for more accuracy. So I can say that you will be attaching all the models. In that case, the response time will be close to 120 to 150 seconds.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, my Docker is working, so I think I can run my UVicon.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the one.
Krish NAik: So, everybody, please try to execute the command you will be having in your README.file. So, if you check here your README file.
Krish NAik: EVCon app main, just like last time, if you have worked with. So, see, this is the command.
Krish NAik: If you want port and those things, okay, otherwise directly UV…
Krish NAik: Even, like, UV run is not required, only this is fine. Okay, in whichever way you want to do the execution, just be sure it's working.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you will see that the application startup is done, and then in the next step, I think,
Krish NAik: I can open my local host 8000 slash docs.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just check.
Krish NAik: And, be sure your Docker container is running. See, if your Docker container is not running, you will get an error.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if Docker container is not running, you will be getting an error.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you can see, by default, it created the collection, CRAG underscore documents. So, if you want to have a check now, previously, when I started the application, you will see here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I try to do a reload of this one, you will see that, okay, CRAP documents came this time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so by default, I've kept it. Like that, always check for this. If this is not available, create it.
Krish NAik: Rahul is telling my Docker container is running, but
Krish NAik: I think it should work,
Krish NAik: because I'm passing localhost 633, I'm not using 000, so I think site cannot be reached.
Krish NAik: That's really, like… There is nothing to change here.
Krish NAik: Because I know that if Docker is running here, Because, C.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the port 000.
Krish NAik: Alright, creation of new CGRAC documents, is that taking place?
Krish NAik: Because in the course, I've just kept that simple logic. First of all, check the services available.
Krish NAik: the Docker container service, if it is available, check that whether this collection is available or not. If the collection is not available, create the collection.
Krish NAik: it's not about closing the browser, you have to just check from your docker, do this, okay, and from your Docker, the service should be available. If the service is not available, then…
Krish NAik: it can create a problem. So, others, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Like, for how many of you can see this?
Krish NAik: Working, Punam Panda, okay, so I think Punam Nanda, okay. Alright, what about others? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, working, working, working. People see, really, like, there is no signs that I've kept it.
Krish NAik: The simple logic already. One thing you can do, please use port.
Krish NAik: Don't use the parameter of put.
Krish NAik: Because I think the parameter of port is creating the issue.
Krish NAik: And don't use host and port like me.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: just pass only till reload. Because 000.host, if it is in Windows, I think there… you might be facing some problems. In Windows, we don't work with 000.
Krish NAik: Okay, so don't use the parameter of host 00. By default, keep it 127.0.0.1, port 8000.
Krish NAik: Okay? Momat is telling, that worked after removing, alright. So, people, please do that change, okay? So, according to your documentation, I think that's why in documentation also, I have kept it only till this point, okay? So, please start the application with only this command. Don't use host, or don't use both.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: So I'm telling remove the port, it's working, I have now npm parallel, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, Poonam is telling, it's working great. Rahul is telling.
Krish NAik: Hell, check, failed.
Krish NAik: And to quadrant… No… Which is just saying there is a download happening for Rapid OCR.
Krish NAik: When I make the call, then it will happen, Mitesh, but not right now.
Krish NAik: Now, Sampad is telling you, watch files detected, no, no, no, no, see. That is your .env.
Krish NAik: And, leave that. That is a warning from watch files package, nothing to worry. When you will upload the file, then it will happen. Yes. Not for now.
Krish NAik: What is the URL for Quadrant? It's given in your config.file, guys.
Krish NAik: Always check the code, config. When I go to config, here you can see. HTTP localhost 6…
Krish NAik: 1. So just be sure here you are not using 000, so don't change any code here. Keep it local 06333, that is much better.
Krish NAik: If you have taken that, then I think it should be up and working.
Krish NAik: It's shown in the console docker when, running too, yes.
Krish NAik: Logo 06333, yes, from here also you can get it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for how many of you, this particular implementation is not working, please let me know. Because the other solution I know, simply, like, create a cloud account and attach your API key and those things that you can do.
Krish NAik: But I think it should work.
Krish NAik: Saurav is telling Title Quadrant Vector Search Engine, alright.
Krish NAik: Mmm… Not running for me. How to see the collection? Just open your UI.
Krish NAik: Open your 633 UI.
Krish NAik: So, just add the word slash dashboard. So, from there, you can see CRAG underscore documents. This will be created.
Krish NAik: It is working on the image alright, Mudda, sir, it's working. Rahul is telling, not working for me. And Milind is telling, not working for me. MSA is asking, where can I get their quadrant API key?
Krish NAik: I'm not using any quadrant API key, but if you want to do that, Okay, so Millin then…
Krish NAik: Rahul, see, generally it should work. Okay, I need to look into what type of issue is there.
Krish NAik: For safety check, what you can do, just go to Quadrant, create an account. Okay, when you do that, from there also, you can get the endpoint and the API key. That is the other way.
Krish NAik: Because I'm not done that integration, but I feel that it should work.
Krish NAik: Okay, so when you do a login into the cloud one.
Krish NAik: people who are, again, getting the issue. For them only, I'm suggesting
Krish NAik: Because generally, like, locally it should be picked up, but again, like, sometimes there can be problem.
Krish NAik: Mmm, just wait.
Krish NAik: People… see, these are development-level issues, you need to sort it out. Okay, so for example, you can create a free cluster, I think there is a 2GB or 3GB limit. Okay, so just give a name, CRAG, okay, underscore, just try to use the same name for now, whichever that we are passing.
Krish NAik: Okay, I will do that, right now, just wait.
Krish NAik: Where is my… I'm just…
Krish NAik: I will test it, because CRAG documents CSS as well.
Krish NAik: AWS, nearest region… Yes, North Virginia, Frankfurt.
Krish NAik: Nearest to me is Frankfurt, only let's go with Frankfurt.
Krish NAik: Okay, 1GB, 4GB, people, like, for whom locally is not working, please create a cloud cluster and pass those
Krish NAik: credentials, okay? Now, as you can see, this is the API key. If you really want it, copy that API key, and you can paste it here. Because I'll be doing some code-level changes, but later on, okay, as you can see, quadrant underscore URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I go to my… this one… That is…
Krish NAik: My dot ENV dot ENV is here.
Krish NAik: I guess?
Krish NAik: Okay, this… Is my first one.
Krish NAik: And then the cluster endpoint.
Krish NAik: And these things directly, you can pick it up from your config. In your config, when you go here, the first one is the quadrant URL.
Krish NAik: Until you can keep it here.
Krish NAik: I think maybe it is.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I've done changes in the code. People who want to do it, please do. If working locally, then please skip that part. Okay, so now I will just, close this one.
Krish NAik: Let me just do the final verification, because I think…
Krish NAik: Just change in config.py. You don't need to change, I think, config.py, just you need to pass them in .env. In config.py, like, if you want, you can do that, but, let me see.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think that, endpoint URL, no, I need actually just…
Krish NAik: Okay, if it works, enjoy suite.
Krish NAik: This is my one, okay.
Krish NAik: Because here, also, you have the dashboard. Can you see automatically, yes, it got connected, it looks like. Okay? So… fine. You don't need to change anything in config.py, just pass it and…
Krish NAik: dot VNP. In whichever way you want, everything I have tested it, so it's working fine. Okay? So, I will simply close it now, and I will switch back to my implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just switch back.
Krish NAik: Because, let me just put in hash, let me just put in hash.
Krish NAik: Okay, and code S. Alright, now I will start my application.
Krish NAik: People for whom not working, I've shown you a simple solution, please do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the rest, UVCon, app main reload. Okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, MSI got Unicom running output, but can't see anything on localhost. You should see on localhost, I feel that.
Krish NAik: Please, people, let me know. Now, Mohit, which are you asking why we are using Quadrant API key?
Krish NAik: Quadrant is a vector.
Krish NAik: database. If you want a cloud-based implementation, then only you need an API key. If you want a Docker-based implementation, Moit, you do need an API key, because they're running locally.
Krish NAik: So I have shown both the implementation. Use cloud or use local. I think by this time, you guys can figure it out. Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because local should also work, but again, rather than spending a lot of time in decoding, use the cloud one.
Krish NAik: Because I feel it should be up and working. Yes?
Krish NAik: That I have not checked, in detail, the one with respect to DocX and others, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Paul, last week I could not, could you play a repo? Last repo was Advanced Rack Tutorials. Okay, so that is the repo. Advanced Rack Tutorials. There, we have the implementation of CRAG in SRAC.
Krish NAik: With query transformations, you can look… have a look into that Devojati.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, please let me know now, can I start the application?
Krish NAik: Because, when I try to do… let me see… yes, Docs is opening, okay? Now, just wait. Here, a unique ID for your upload folder.
Krish NAik: Let me just delete this one for now.
Krish NAik: We'll put trash.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is a new vector DB, so I think it will be pretty much a clean version. Let me try to upload a document here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think Dockic is not there, really, like, I've not tested, I, just tested with a PDF.
Krish NAik: For now, so I think… Let me just pass one.
Krish NAik: Now, let me see that, whether it's working or not.
Krish NAik: For the first time, it will take… okay, because few backend with respect to docklings that are configured, so that rapid OCR takes time.
Krish NAik: Now, Cloud API for Quadrant is also not working, Rahul is telling.
Krish NAik: Rahul, if Quadrant Cloud API is also not working.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'll read.
Krish NAik: So, total chunks created, 209. Okay, now…
Krish NAik: I have used a hybrid Shankar concept, okay, and here, really, I've not kept any,
Krish NAik: chunking information directly, based on that, should I maintain any chunks like? Last time in Project 2, I have done that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that case, 209 chunks. 209 chunks is really a lot, I hope you guys understand.
Krish NAik: So, here, you guys can actually improve the chunking by adding some information, like, try… where you try to maintain a minimum chunk size and the maximum chunk size.
Krish NAik: Because that implementation, I have shown in Project 2. So I'm not worried about here. Because the strategy is exactly the same. On top of your hybrid chunker, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, GPT is not gonna query catch… exactly, Subhash. Exactly. That is the main purpose of that GPT one that I showed.
Krish NAik: Now, Abhijit is telling, for me, 8000 is not working. I changed to port 9000, but still picks up 8000, debugging it. Okay, alright? Nangra is telling,
Krish NAik: One validation error, probably. Please do check, and don't change the config file. Whatever change that you want to do, do it in .env naga.
Krish NAik: File format is not allowed for,
Krish NAik: File, type text. Alright, really, I'm not…
Krish NAik: done the testing with text, I have just passed, I think, only one, which is this PDF formula.
Krish NAik: Because…
Krish NAik: ingestion was not my priority, I hope you get that. Later on, next Saturday, everything, or tomorrow, I can install those fixes.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, working fine. What is the purpose of Tabula API key? Tabula API Key is a web search part, Amar Saintivas.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you can use a free version, just like last time. We have used DuckDuckGo.
Krish NAik: Even Brave Search… previously, Brave Search was cheaper. I think just this month, they have increased the pricing for Brave Search also, because I got to me, there was a change with respect to their pricing.
Krish NAik: That is fineMS. That is slash favicon.ico, even I get that.
Krish NAik: Okay, not found, somewhere, like, I'll be also getting that, don't worry. That is not a problem.
Krish NAik: If you change that particular browser, okay, I think even in my case, I'll be having that, okay?
Krish NAik: Just to be twins.
Krish NAik: Everybody.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes, so… people, please have a check, otherwise I will look. Okay, so I think we can go for a break, it's already a long one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in the meantime…
Krish NAik: Okay, Rahul is telling, it's working fine now. Okay, Rahul, you sort it out great. Okay, yeah, yeah, brake only, because I forgot for initial configuration, but fine.
Krish NAik: We have time, so nothing to worry about. This is my desktop, where is my…
Krish NAik: clock, CLO clock running, just wait.
Krish NAik: Deva Choti, the architecture is there inside the workflow folder.
Krish NAik: People who are asking.
Krish NAik: So just be sure, if you try to upload a document, you are getting some type of response.
Krish NAik: Is there a website, I won't say there is a direct website.
Krish NAik: like, you can ask some AI and make your prompt much more better. That I've seen people do.
Krish NAik: Dead.
Krish NAik: There is prompt.fyi, I think, something like that. That is also good. Though, no, those are pre-written prompts of somebody.
Krish NAik: Okay, Abhisheic. But again, like, prompt-level optimization and other things.
Krish NAik: Because I'm planning a lecture for prompt…
Krish NAik: optimization, okay, with respect to catching also.
Krish NAik: But again, a little bit, because… I'm planning, let me see.
Krish NAik: I don't create nothing from scratch.
Krish NAik: Pretty much AI.
Krish NAik: Right now, like, I told you last week, I've been using Kimi a lot.
Krish NAik: In your case, most of the code that he was seeing is written by Kimi.
Krish NAik: The boilerplate was done by GLM4.7.
Krish NAik: Okay, but, like, generally, like, it's good that when you are planning, you use something good.
Krish NAik: Okay, once the plan is done, then you can use any type of model, because I think GLM also launched the recent version of that model. I have not used it, but this week I'll be doing the testing.
Krish NAik: Roadmap for Agents, yes.
Krish NAik: We can. Alto, it was OPA's 4.6 is really… it's very costly.
Krish NAik: That's why. Navish is telling Rapid OCR download failed for me.
Krish NAik: Alright, if rapid OCR is failing, because I think it should work.
Krish NAik: Just wait, because 10 minutes timer, just think that we will start from 11.15.
Krish NAik: Just wait. If I start sharing the other screen…
Krish NAik: This is desktop 3, I think.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Because I have used a default implementation, Up, huh…
Krish NAik: docklink, where I've not, changed anything here.
Krish NAik: So, probably, like, if rapid OCR is not supporting in your system, change the OCR backend.
Krish NAik: That is the other way around, okay? So…
Krish NAik: If you want to switch to, some others, like Tesseract and others, Okay.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Because then, manually, you have to do the change here, for whoever, like, if you want to do that particular change. So here, can you see, with respect to easy OCR option, Tesseract OCR, like, whichever OCR that you want to work with Abhishek, okay?
Krish NAik: This is the main OCR-based implementation. From here, you can look into the documentation, and you can update that.
Krish NAik: Abhijit is telling, as per the document, UV run, UVCon, always pick 8,000, so this…
Krish NAik: UV run is not required, you can just use UVCon, like, in my case, even if you see, I'm not using… because already I know I'm inside a virtual environment, so UV run is not required.
Krish NAik: Okay, Abhi. So, like, you can, do that. I think by default, it's picking up that one.
Krish NAik: getting buffer error now, alright? It works for me now, already, right?
Krish NAik: Alright, I think most of you have fixed and looked into that issue, it's great.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Amar Sinivas is telling the following commands are shadowed by other commands in your UVUVX.
Krish NAik: Alright, like, people can use UV as well as UVX, so when you first install UV, then both the things are available.
Krish NAik: Now, docker run hyphen p, quadrant slash quadrant failed to connect to Docker API Unix.
Krish NAik: Amerson, you will just check Docker is running or not. If Docker is not running, then only you get this particular error, fail to connect.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Which command we have to use to run the Docker image. For Docker image, you have the command readme, the command is, like, docker run hyphen P, then the Docker port with your system port, 6336333, I think.
Krish NAik: I have it in my, README, README, README, where is my README?
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you have that.
Krish NAik: So, this is line number 109 in README, docker run hyphen T. People who want to do that.
Krish NAik: That is not an error.
Krish NAik: gate slash favicon.ico lib dot rajasika. That is not an error. You don't need to fix that.
Krish NAik: That is from browser, if you're through browser when you try to access it.
Krish NAik: Now, Abhisheim was telling, I've got a mail from Academy that a year plan is available for us. Year plan? Okay, ROV also including that, next LLM? No, no, no.
Krish NAik: Those advanced batches doesn't come under subscriptions, they will be pretty much out of the subscription.
Krish NAik: Other batches, like anything, the normal version, those will come within option, but not those advanced ones.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, just wait, okay? Let me just eat something, okay, and then I think what's the time?
Krish NAik: It's 11-11, okay? Just give me 5 minutes, okay?
Krish NAik: And then we will start.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so I'm back. Okay, now somebody's asking, how much money was quadrant underscore endpoint? Please check in your config.g. I think it's… will be quadrant URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, and don't change your config.py, please change your .env file, that is one.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, quadrant and point… okay, alright. For upload, we need an API key? Yes, yes, OpenAIK API API key is required.
Krish NAik: If it says invalid, please try to look into that part.
Krish NAik: Because after 2 to 3 minutes, then I will start that part. Swagger you guys come, now we have to upload the PDF. Please just try to upload a PDF and check that the upload functionality is working. Then I will look into the query part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so step by step. The upload route I have checked, so for you also, the upload route should be working. Because if upload is not working, query cannot perform. I hope everybody understands.
Krish NAik: So, if upload is not working, then query, nothing you can do.
Krish NAik: OCR issues are coming, then manually you need to change that one. OCR part, because rapid OCR… I know in Linux and Mac-based systems, you won't have a problem, but
Krish NAik: With respect to, I think, Windows, you might have a problem.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: upload working already. People like Abhijit, the same thing, models, scope.c and models rapidi.
Krish NAik: You're selling manually to get that model path, and you have to place it.
Krish NAik: According to the error that you are getting.
Krish NAik: As always, the other option is, Abhijay, change it from Rapid OCR to other OCR. Just now, I shared it, no, according to the official documentation.
Krish NAik: Hmm… You can always have a change.
Krish NAik: Just quick.
Krish NAik: Mmm, I think… This is my desktop 3.
Krish NAik: There was that documentation from here.
Krish NAik: So here, the main… during the, PDF conversion, whenever you are passing, so from here, like, which Tesseract OCR, okay, for, like, Rapid OCR, default is this one, like, EV OCR, whichever you want to use it.
Krish NAik: You can do that particular change according to your own operating system.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's get back, because we have checked one of the routes.
Krish NAik: Now, I think I can get back here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, let's start with the query part, okay? Because I think query slash compare
Krish NAik: Even, like, we will do the testing later on, but first of all, let's check with SlashQuin.
Krish NAik: Raja Shekhar, that is correct, no. There is nothing wrong with that.
Krish NAik: Paddle Paddle OCR is good, EC OCR is also good.
Krish NAik: Rapid OCR… It's also good, but it's better to switch to some
Krish NAik: cloud vision one. Parallel OCR has recently launched one, but other than that, newer models also, last time, Matesh, I told, like, GLM OCR, those type of versions, like, deep-seq OCR takes a lot of time, so I feel at least GLM is a much lightweight version that you can use.
Krish NAik: All right, now let me start working with the query modes. Okay, so for you also, you can see query is basically a string. Mode, there are four different modes in our application. One is a standard, CRAG, self-reflective, and both. Okay, so let's start with, standard.
Krish NAik: Okay, and with respect to mood types, I think, you can get it from your README file.
Krish NAik: Somewhere in your README file, it will be written.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: Okay, so standard CRAG, okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Yes, C rag is there, self underscore reflective rag is there, booth is there. Okay, fine.
Krish NAik: So, let's start with the standard one. By default, see, like, enable ID, you can make it true, or enable re-ranking, you can make it true.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because I know, like, in my case, if I try to… this is the first time, so let me just make it true. Later on, another basis, I'll be switching that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always, look into the terminal, what is exactly going on.
Krish NAik: defaulted.
Krish NAik: So, Heidi generated 3 hypothetical documents, Heidi, written 3 unique chunks. From the hypotheticals, then comes re-ranking 3 chunks with your local cross-encoder, loading the local model into the system, model loaded successfully, re-ranking is completed, returning top 3 chunks.
Krish NAik: Now, like, based on that, whatever?
Krish NAik: So, climate change refers to long alternations in global patterns, okay, like, whatever the thing that is coming, I know this is the standard version right now, and this is my metadata information that I have kept it, which is under my chunk.
Krish NAik: Fintech model, so all those information that I have here.
Krish NAik: based on, multiple keywords, at least, like, what are the major keywords in every chunk, that I was actually trying to look through a,
Krish NAik: Like, this implementation is not based on NER, a separate, model.
Krish NAik: But, that can be added here through lang extract or linear V2.
Krish NAik: So right now, based on the results, when I look into, the scores are really towards the lower side, I don't feel…
Krish NAik: Okay, because what is the query that I have passed? Because the query is string.
Krish NAik: Now, I will change the actual query to your main one, okay?
Krish NAik: Now you will see you will be getting better results.
Krish NAik: What are the impacts?
Krish NAik: of climate change.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, for sure, let's get back here.
Krish NAik: Now, those scores will improve from minus 10 to at least better version, because last time I didn't pass anything.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, re-ranking actually took time. Okay, so let's see…
Krish NAik: Here, I can see, yes, for sure, the results are better now compared. Based on the chunk, I can see the scores are much higher. 8, okay, the first chunk was player, like, playing much…
Krish NAik: Better role. Initial retriever crown 3, re-ranking is true. Okay. So, all those major things that I have done it. So, this is the standard version, and it's working great.
Krish NAik: So, please do have a check with your standard version.
Krish NAik: I can see everybody's message, okay?
Krish NAik: Could you please share the PC? This is the same PDF file. Under Strat Climate Change, I've been using that for one… more than one month, Latish.
Krish NAik: But if you work that, just wait,
Krish NAik: Nagash, why taking long time to read the PDF? When you are doing it for the first time, it takes time. After that, it's a one-time thing for your main OCR backend. Because of that, it takes.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Rajat, okay, that's in your config.py, I think your re-ranker has… there, see. I have updated that code in my local 2, 3. If in your code, I think this number…
Krish NAik: of re-ragar is 20. Okay, so just be sure, like, what is the number? That is according to the code.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: You have not applied hybrid renting till now? Yes, I think.
Krish NAik: hybrid ranking.
Krish NAik: Hmm, just wait.
Krish NAik: My main document service…
Krish NAik: One is the ensure collection of third, query character, query point… Filter…
Krish NAik: I think… I have not added that one.
Krish NAik: Because…
Krish NAik: Here, the main one I have not added, it looks like.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, let me change the standard to…
Krish NAik: The purpose of CRAC, I will try to perform a different type of question.
Krish NAik: Let's try to pass something out of… The vector DB, okay?
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: What is the current weather in New Delhi?
Krish NAik: Okay, let me see that, see that fall back to web search or not, okay? And by these… I'm making it false, because here, really, these things doesn't matter to me.
Krish NAik: Let me make it false for now.
Krish NAik: Double Heidi, let me… do an execution.
Krish NAik: the current weather in Delhi is 21. I can see that, yes, the web search fallback that we had, it's working fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on the query that is coming, though it is not related, but in the sources, I'm keeping the
Krish NAik: actual, sources, like, without that particular knowledge. Now, there are some temperature-related things with respect to extreme weathers and global temperatures. I feel now that is being, through by your main
Krish NAik: I can say the default rack, or the standard rack one.
Krish NAik: Okay? Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, if I just, check back, okay, so here, if I switch back…
Krish NAik: Because, based on the keywords, the score, at least it's somewhere better, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Oh, it really does force,
Krish NAik: the chunks are… doesn't play a crucial role to… we are… Now, in this rack details, you can see web, web search is equal to true.
Krish NAik: Because with respect to evaluation, relevance 0, relevance level irrelevant, confidence 1, evaluation method, LLM greater right now, needs web search, which is equal to true, evaluated at all rate.
Krish NAik: Fine, so from, the response type, finally I can say that.
Krish NAik: And these are all null, null, because I have not applied anything in the response type right now. Okay? So if you want to apply, then you can do that.
Krish NAik: Now, in this particular condition.
Krish NAik: Please check and let me know the CRAG implementation with respect to web search is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: Everybody. Because the standard one I have tested, and the CRAC one I have tested. Next, I will test the self underscore reflective.
Krish NAik: Is this ID? If you want to enable ID, please enable ID by making this condition as true.
Krish NAik: Whoever is asking, Mantage and others, okay?
Krish NAik: Well, right now, I don't want any type of web search, so just wait, let me copy that particular parameter.
Krish NAik: I think in my ReadMe, I have this self underscore reflective.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I cannot ask any other thing. Self-reflective means it has to be from the main one. So, the same question that I asked last time.
Krish NAik: What are the impacts of climate change?
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, enable Heidi, let me see. Now, this will take time.
Krish NAik: Because the number of max iterations in my case is 3.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, if I go back…
Krish NAik: Retrieve 5 chunks from the query, self-reflective iteration 1, reflection score, you can see 1, grounded is equal to true, self-reflective answer is approved. And based on that, answer is approved, which means that I'll be getting the response.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, what happens if I try to pass something, like, what is the weather of Delhi with respect to self-rav?
Krish NAik: What should be the response? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is the final reflection detail, source cited, needs regeneration, false, reflection result, all claims made in the generated answer are directly supported. Always look into this JSON-based response. Here, you have majorly all the information which is required.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I'll be changing this self-reflection. Here, I'll be adding that statement back.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: That's great.
Krish NAik: Tell me the weather in New Delhi.
Krish NAik: Okay, now when I pass this parameter, so what should be the, response? You can do the testing by yourself also, because in self-reflective module, we don't have a web search, okay? So here, let's see what we are getting.
Krish NAik: Fairfield reflection, iteration 1, reflection score 0.20, grounded is equal to false.
Krish NAik: Self-reflective is telling refining the query and retrying.
Krish NAik: Now, the refined queries, what are the current weather conditions and climate trends in New Delhi? Retrieve 5 chunks, self-reflection, now iteration 2, reflection score is 0.2, grounded is equal to false. Because the max number of checks that I have kept it is actually, like, 012 in the third condition.
Krish NAik: Now, whatever the thing that came from, it will be shown in the response.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the provided documents do not contain specific information about the current weather in New Delhi. They discuss broader topics related to climate change, and I feel that this is correct.
Krish NAik: Yes, it will do 3 retransions by default, it is kept in the code.
Krish NAik: You can update that number of iterations to more, but the response time will be much higher.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, this particular query also I've checked. Now, let me…
Krish NAik: Change it to… now I will move to the next mode.
Krish NAik: So what do I want everybody? Because initial testing, please do it, then tomorrow, every, like, code by code, we can do the discussion. Now, I'm switching on the both mode. Both mode means the combination of CRAC plus SRAT, okay? Now, this is where
Krish NAik: If I try to do the execution, let's see what is the response.
Krish NAik: Tell me the… let me add the word current.
Krish NAik: Current.
Krish NAik: And let me see.
Krish NAik: And this is not an interrogative sentence, so fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, as per the query, so first of all, your main retriever from their 5 chunks, according to the query, CRAG evaluation, it's saying that it is irrelevant. It means that if something is irrelevant, you need to trigger the web search. So, web search has been triggered.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, from web search, we got 3 results. Now, more difficult to vote, so using those 3 chunks for our self-reflection, which are from 3 from Web Search.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, first iteration, reflection score 1, grounded is equal to true, done.
Krish NAik: So, now, this is the place, if you really look into the content. So, the current weather is as follows, temperature is 21.1, condition, mist, and other things that are coming.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, one thing, you have to be sure that you are maintaining the chunk structure in such a way, because you need to convert that web data also into a chunk format, which yourself rack can digest it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I have done that conversion of, like, the return type of your search result into your chunk, model structure for PyTic.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do have a check, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Because majorly, all the ones, both ones I have tested, So it should work.
Krish NAik: Tatish is telling getting 500 error while uploading the document. The error can be with respect to the OCR backend.
Krish NAik: And generally, like, previously in Project 2, you guys have used the same OCR.
Krish NAik: So, I have used the same OCR, I thought about not changing anything.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please let me know that part, so I think here… This is my cloud cluster.
Krish NAik: You know, these are my…
Krish NAik: Documents contained… okay. Now, can you see here, this is my actual payload? The length of the vector is 1536.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes, this is actually how it looks like. So, please let me know, with respect to the core functionality. Saurav, I had to step out to kindly share the location to upload the file.
Krish NAik: Kindly share the location to upload the file, like,
Krish NAik: able to download the Rapid OCR? Alright, Rapid OCR is working fine, then fine. Whichever backend works for you. I know Tesserate will work for everybody.
Krish NAik: That's the default one.
Krish NAik: Kindly share the location to upload the file, or I could not get that part.
Krish NAik: Corp BPN. Okay, probably BPNs might block, I'm not sure about that part.
Krish NAik: I'm getting 500 internal error. 500 internal error, so please check which, service, like, which service is throwing that, whether the LLM service, the vector service, the document service, you have multiple services, Satish.
Krish NAik: So, from your terminal, please do have a check and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Others, in the meantime, please test all the major four ones.
Krish NAik: Okay, even I have not tested my,
Krish NAik: I think there was another route, no? Because initially, I have tested this route before the class, but this compare mode, even I have not tested. Let me test it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, so whatever the query, let me just pass it from here only.
Krish NAik: This is upload query, okay.
Krish NAik: Let me see whether this route works or not.
Krish NAik: Because of this route, I have not tested before.
Krish NAik: Okay, standard is coming. I'm unable to provide, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, with the main sources, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Then in the next step, okay, I can see the compare is also, worry, because the CRAG response is correct, when I look into that.
Krish NAik: Whereas, when I look into the implementations, Op.
Krish NAik: Let me see… self-reflective rag.
Krish NAik: This is the web search results that coming from Weatherapi.com.
Krish NAik: Self-reflective answer, the provided document do not contain any answer about the current weather in New Delhi. This is good.
Krish NAik: And now, finally, I think I have that,
Krish NAik: Reflected at, no. Let me look into that both.
Krish NAik: I think booth is not there under this particular API.
Krish NAik: So, please have a check, because I can see that, yes, this API is also working fine.
Krish NAik: Because I haven't created a lot of APIs, like, for clearing your vector store, for other things in the last time, the main focus was towards the core application, that's why I've kept it pretty much for query and upload.
Krish NAik: Other things, we can add it, as you guys already know. Like, from project 2, we can pick up those wider plates, and we can use it.
Krish NAik: Both is not there. Both is not there. Which one is not there? Yes, both is not there in the compare mode.
Krish NAik: In the compare, simply, like, we are comparing those
Krish NAik: Three things. The standard, the CRAG, and the self-reflective rag.
Krish NAik: Yes, Atish, please change your CRBs to backend.
Krish NAik: documentation, it will take only first time. It takes time. First time. Once you have done it first time, after that MS, it should not take a long time.
Krish NAik: First time, because in your backend, Rapid OCR gets git installed.
Krish NAik: No, I think, Rajat, you can drop today.
Krish NAik: Because this is the main, thing that I was going to discuss, and I feel that this part is done.
Krish NAik: Because then, tomorrow, To the next part.
Krish NAik: Tan is asking what is the real-time use case at any point of time, like, this can be used.
Krish NAik: To improve your results, son.
Krish NAik: Real-time people are using web search tools, so that's why corrective RAG implementation is widely used in any RAG implementation.
Krish NAik: So, when you ask real-time.
Krish NAik: focus on the features, the features that I have shown, and if you think about any real-time lag-based project, you will be always doing these integrations.
Krish NAik: Panto's just telling for, advanced, like, I know that I have an implementation just to it.
Krish NAik: This is yourself underscore ratsantush.
Krish NAik: Please check, guys, before telling, please check at least the report. I know that it is there.
Krish NAik: Alright, please let me know people who have problems.
Krish NAik: For… I think for most of you, it should work. The implementation is really simple. As we have not focused on other functionalities, these are the core functionality. And CRAC implementation, every time in any rack, when you are trying to making it productionized.
Krish NAik: Vinny, if you feel that, you should have access to the outer ecosystem.
Krish NAik: Okay, then you can add this web search.
Krish NAik: If you feel that, yes, to my current users, I don't want to provide that.
Krish NAik: Functionality of web search. Leave it.
Krish NAik: Use some type of external retriever as a fallback.
Krish NAik: Okay, like your company documents, or something like that, or some type of FAQs.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we can create a rule for FAQs. If something doesn't come, FAQ, like, contact HR, contact these things, which we can do.
Krish NAik: If I shut down server, will I have to upload the document again? No, that is, if you delete the Docker container, then you have to do it.
Krish NAik: Emmet.
Krish NAik: The application is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay. People who see… Rapid OCR Naga, please change your backend.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: not directly…
Krish NAik: Don't tell me that, yes, this is… because I know you need to debug and you need to troubleshoot these things.
Krish NAik: Facing the same, when I shut down Docker, quadrant deleted all the chunks. Yes, if you shut down Docker, it means that what? That container which was live.
Krish NAik: It's gone.
Krish NAik: what you can do, Mitesh, in that case, like, with your Docker, you can mount a persistent storage, because otherwise you use the cloud option.
Krish NAik: In cloud, everything is in persistent methiche. That's why I showed that also in the class.
Krish NAik: Now, people with respect to doubts, okay, they can, let me know.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that for most of you, it should work desktop, and people who have changed that OCR background, they can also, raise their hands. I can take some questions on that.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Okay, so participants, I think 4 people have done.
Krish NAik: I'll be Jeet?
Krish NAik: Jagapati… Okay, then Krishna Prasvanth.
Krish NAik: Do people have… Alright, so one by one, I think you guys can go ahead.
Krish NAik: People who have done the change, I think, Abhijit, if you have done that, you can let me know.
Krish NAik: Yeah.
Prusty, Abhijit: Paul, what I… Paul, what I wanted to know, like, in the document processor, we are using the default document converter file, right?
Krish NAik: Yes. So, first, the self-converter.
Prusty, Abhijit: I just wanted to understand, like, how does it internally understand, like, it has to take the rapid osse here? Like, it is…
Prusty, Abhijit: default order?
Krish NAik: default, default.
Prusty, Abhijit: Okay, and how does it understand, like, it has to download from the URL? Is it in their codebase, or we define it?
Krish NAik: No, like, it is in Docklinks, not in our.
Prusty, Abhijit: healthcare.
Prusty, Abhijit: Okay
Prusty, Abhijit: Sure, sure, that's it for… I'm just trying to check… change to Tesseract to see how does it work.
Krish NAik: No, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Lake…
Krish NAik: we have the… if you remove Dopplink, then you have to understand that you have to change that entire thing. Like, you can bring both the things from Langchain, okay, like document letters from Langchain, as well as text splitters from Langchain.
Krish NAik: That is something…
Prusty, Abhijit: When I remove it, it is failing in other, or upload in other places. I was just debugging it.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine.
Krish NAik: Next.
Krish NAik: Next, next, next. Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Anshu, me, sir, Anshu, alright? Anshu, just wait, okay? I will unmute you. Amas, Sriniva, Sates, Tiwari, everybody, like, I have unmuted immediately. Most of you.
Amarsrinivas: iPhone.
Krish NAik: Yes, word.
Amarsrinivas: Paul, actually, I'm asking, while testing CRAG, I'm also asking, other than the document which I uploaded, like, tell me about Amher Sreenverse. So, then it is giving old, profile history, like, currently I have 20 years.
Amarsrinivas: But now it is… maybe it's pulling from somewhere 9.2 experience of my profile details.
Amarsrinivas: So…
Krish NAik: According to the similarity such.
Amarsrinivas: similarity search. So, ideally, if it is web search, it should retrieve the latest information, right?
Krish NAik: Okay, no, no, no. So, like, that, I thought you uploaded some resume and that. Exactly, like, now that is from web search. See, in web search, now you have to check, like, the written type of taboo.
Amarsrinivas: Oh, okay.
Krish NAik: Because now, Table, now that information, probably if I'm taking it as in LinkedIn, now from LinkedIn, it will go, and it will look that… because exactly, they are also from Table, you can look into what are the type of sources that I've not added in code, but it is possible. Like, the actual URLs from where you were getting the answer.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, because I see these are, Tableis giving old information. Earlier, duckling search is at least better than this, that's what I observed.
Krish NAik: This is the same docklink is an internal thing, no? Like, web search, you have to test, or.
Amarsrinivas: Doug, go search, something yesterday.
Krish NAik: And the DuckDuckGo program, because I feel Table is good, but again, like, to search…
Amarsrinivas: For that particular purpose.
Krish NAik: again, like, it might fail sometimes, not a full fruit one, because DuckDuckoo is fine, last time we have used that. We can use that, but again, like, in production, we don't use so much DuckDuckoo, that's why. It's a search and table is the main used one.
Krish NAik: Ivy.
Amarsrinivas: And one… one more question I have is, nowadays, in every company, Microsoft guys and AWS guys, they are coming up and giving co-pilot co-work and everything, and they are enabling 365 license, right?
Amarsrinivas: There also, without doing all these things, if we… our documents are there in the folder or somewhere, it is already giving a similar.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Amarsrinivas: And also, this web option is also there. And similarly, in AWS AmazonQ, I used, where we can train our own, we can connect to S3, or database, or anything. We can create our own things.
Amarsrinivas: So, is it… how… is it really, I know you were giving the core foundation concepts, I agree. This is really help for us, but when we present something, is it a decision for the companies, like, whether we make or,
Amarsrinivas: Build our… make our bike.
Krish NAik: Now the question comes, are you building a product or you are building a surface?
Krish NAik: If you're building a product, Then, then these things will.
Amarsrinivas: are required, okay.
Krish NAik: If you're not building a product, really, why it matters, simply, like, drag and drop pipelines and other things.
Krish NAik: Because when you feel that I need customizations, then only things are important to go in-depth.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, pretty much high-level stuff quickly, like, one day wrap-up.
Amarsrinivas: Damn.
Krish NAik: can be done.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, this is… really, foundation helps us when we build custom products, I agree. Yeah, because I'm just thinking, how customers outside, are they everyone relying on this Microsoft AWS, or are they really building their own custom LLM, is my question.
Krish NAik: Not everybody, like, RAG-based solutions are much more custom, I can say, because company, internally, you can think about there will be certain problem statements where RAG will fit.
Krish NAik: more than 20 to 30% use cases in every organization that I know. When you really try to understand, there are problems in, like, finance department, HR, everywhere.
Amarsrinivas: For internal employees only, like, I feel more than…
Krish NAik: 10% of the times, rags are tough.
Krish NAik: To automate the stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for that, pretty much drag and drop and other things, like 2 developers and 3 developers work, and they make the solution, because that's for internal. You are not productionizing it to a certain level. So, things are much easier to implement. But actually, when you try to make it much more scalable product, a lot of other things that need to be taken care of.
Amarsrinivas: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Because here, money comes into the picture just because of debt alone.
Krish NAik: Embedding. The core two things.
Krish NAik: For embeddings also, you need that. For your LLM also, in both the places, one plays a crucial.
Amarsrinivas: So, which one will be more cheaper? Is it make or buy?
Krish NAik: No, no, no. See, generally, if you are working in a company, then that company has always a long-term contract with the cloud providers, like Amazon is there. In that case, the general pricing, for example, if I take… if I sign up an account today in OpenAI, okay, and the amount that I will be getting charged.
Krish NAik: Then in that particular case, the through cloud of my company, it gets more than 60% cheaper.
Amarsrinivas: I agree.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, if you are having a long-term deal, by default, because I know always with, compared to long-term pricing, it comes down to 30-40% of the major ones, directly if you try to go up front, without a long-term commitment.
Amarsrinivas: Thanks, bud.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Alright, others, I think…
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Hi, Father.
Satish Tiwari: So this year.
Krish NAik: Tatish, yes, Tatish.
Satish Tiwari: Yeah, actually, I want to share my screen.
Krish NAik: Satish, you want to share? Let me stop sharing my screen. Yes, Satish, now promoted to panelist, I've added you.
Krish NAik: Next, Jagaphati.
Anshu singh: Hello, Phil?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Anshu singh: Hear me, Anzuzer, can I share?
Krish NAik: Joy, I'm adding you, adding you, adding you to panelists, just to it.
Krish NAik: MS also, and, Naga also.
Krish NAik: Jagapati also. Everyone I have unmuted.
Krish NAik: Jagapati is asking, I want to share my screen, okay? Jagapati, there are two ideas. One is Jagapati Pabu, and the other one is Jagapati.
Krish NAik: Which ID?
Krish NAik: Which ID? Which ID? Quickly tell me. Oh, this one, Jagapati. Okay, alright, I will add you.
Krish NAik: Yes, Devajyoti.
Naga: All of them.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Just to understand the basics out of it, the CREG and Astral implementation, right?
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: So, for example, if I'm running a RAG, and that's not giving the proper output, right, as a response, as an answer.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Then we should use the CRAC, the same question could have been searched through the internet, and we could find the retrieval sum of there, right?
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: And if we still find there is a ambiguity, the scores are not coming more than 0.8,
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Then, in that case, we should use the A strad.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: And we could teach our LLM what exactly.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. CCC. Both the RAG implementations are different. Here, the idea is that
Krish NAik: CRAC for your retrieval level quality check, where you check the query with respect to the chunks, and based on that, you perform a scoring. That is different. So, for your retrieval, I say that use this.
Krish NAik: for my final LLM generation fails for that cell, in both the cases.
Krish NAik: Both have different purpose.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Okay, so ASRAG and CRAG are not interlinked, right? I mean, they have not.
Krish NAik: Not necessary. You can connect them, like I have done it.
Krish NAik: Similarly, like, after this, there is a topic adaptive retrieval will come. In adaptive retrieval, we generally combine both of these things.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Okay. Like, CRAG is actually searching the content out of the internet, ASRAG does not do that, right?
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Please check, yes, last class. When you ask me the questions.
Krish NAik: Okay, these are the basics that I have discussed. When it will do the web search, when it will find that it is irrelevant. Irrelevant means the query with respect to the context, then only it will perform. If it is relevant, then it won't perform. If it is ambiguous, then it will use a combination of both web plus this one.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Yeah, okay, okay.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: But Acerag and CRAG we could combine, if there is a use case we have.
Krish NAik: You can do the combination in my case, like I have done, but these things take much more added time. Self-reflective rag, it totally, like, how many checks you are adding.
Krish NAik: The more number of checks, the response time of the rack can be much more higher, just because of that refinement of the query by the system.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Welcome.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Okay, we'll look into the previous one, I missed out, okay.
Krish NAik: Because in the last class, three topics only I discussed. One was query transformation, CDAS.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Okay, let's dope.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Anshu singh: Yes, sir.
Satish Tiwari: in Richmond?
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Satish Tiwari: Yeah, I'm getting this error, okay, by the way.
Krish NAik: This error I told you, no, this is because of your reproduce here. You need to solve this. One option, change your backend.
Krish NAik: to some other rules here, that official documentation link I have already shared. Again, if you want, I will share that docklink documentation.
Satish Tiwari: I have that now.
Krish NAik: From the docklink documentation, OCR full-page docklink.
Satish Tiwari: Yes.
Krish NAik: Please change the source code.
Naga: Okay, then I will take it for.
Krish NAik: it means that your backend is not working, and by default, it picks up the rapid OCR. What you can do, you can switch to, like, Tesseract is the easiest one, and the other easier options which are there. Class is finished, here's moving.
Krish NAik: Next class, I will be discussing the code, and I think next week we'll start deployment. I'm thinking about ECS with Farget, or Bingstock directly, picking up the easiest one. So, let me see whichever one.
Satish Tiwari: So, we are applicant in this model those BY PIs, right?
Krish NAik: you have to update it. Under the service, you'll be having the document service. In that particular file, you need to update.
Naga: There's a document processor, okay.
Krish NAik: Yes, there's document services there. This document service needs to be updated.
Satish Tiwari: Okay, okay, I'll be good.
Anshu singh: Sir, can I share my screen?
Krish NAik: Somebody from panelists?
Anshu singh: Yes, sir.
Krish NAik: Langshu, you were in panelist start sharing, I thought you were attending.
Naga: I don't have a hearing…
Krish NAik: We were in attending, not in the past.
Anshu singh: Can you see my screen, sir?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Anshu singh: good afternoon, sir, sir. Last week, Manet MOSPI joined here, Ministry of Aesthetics and Program Implementation.
Anshu singh: Government. Then sir, muji ek ye semantic search ka mujahi ye option bilah.
Anshu singh: i semantic AI Adi grata, semantic AI-powered search.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Anshu singh: GDP.
Anshu singh: 2027 ka. Jab ki GDP 2025-26 kaya hai.
Anshu singh: Toh ye semantic search of sa rag mein, matla means retrieval part chore detach hai na.
Krish NAik: Matloop semantic search, matulop utens search yang loop.
Krish NAik: with a semantic search.
Anshu singh: Toh said is project ko kasalit karne abhi ispei Deloitte kabanda kaam karatha. Us seh ye honahi paya, toh fairness, fir kunja finally is the select kyaga, isko banana, semantic search.
Anshu singh: Toh sir, iska mer ko jahat problem samaji mehata data ingestion part ka problem.
Anshu singh: Ungasar sara data government ka, ES2 per khawa.
Anshu singh: database, right?
Anshu singh: hai.
Anshu singh: Tohi amen sir unse CSV leilu, CSV file le kehit data ingestion karu main parsing or embedding space ada diamond.
Krish NAik: semantic search ka baat, alright, mean that you need to vector me convert karna hai.
Krish NAik: It is not possible. Agar SQL hain, agar postgres hai toh pg vector control.
Anshu singh: semantic search viewer.
Krish NAik: Decor.
Anshu singh: Hmm.
Krish NAik: karta.
Anshu singh: official, yeah, no ka.
Krish NAik: internally dekanapatekbar.
Anshu singh: Monday ko, ekbar one-to-one call ragtu, ki ki totala time lag ta'in, muje bhi tumarasag batke.
Krish NAik: Monday go ragdo ya. Monday go kavi bhi mera free umin bara baja selei ke, char baji ke beach mein. Tumor office ke ba, che baji se paletak ka.
Anshu singh: ministry.
Krish NAik: Gris circa flight hai, Pandara tariko.
Krish NAik: Gigma…
Krish NAik: Darius is in sales, so, like, if you guys want to meet that, 17th, say, 19th Dilhi Mehrahenge. So, I think, he's going on 17th, 15th name.
Anshu singh: The contact Kasi over, sir.
Krish NAik: Just wait. I am sharing Daria's numbers in chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think you guys can…
Krish NAik: Directly, WhatsApp in a message, and then he will let you know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so his name is, Darius.
Amarsrinivas: Can we also join, sir, so that, we can also understand?
Krish NAik: Like, it's one-to-one.
Amarsrinivas: Oh, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Because his data, again, that's why. It's not about.
Anshu singh: Sir, si kasi join karenge bunde ko.
Krish NAik: Monday go, muja palli male darna. Meh mail a athi, mein calendar.
Anshu singh: Okay, sir, require mail ID bhi apna yoga government cool job.
Krish NAik: APP at the red krishnaike.in, notion mein liharata.
Anshu singh: Okay, no sensitive limitations.
Krish NAik: Notion cap, first page may… your table a table, man.
Krish NAik: Dear…
Anshu singh: O-B-I-P-I-E-S-E, jantani ya.
Krish NAik: important to yung.
Krish NAik: multi-department cases.
Anshu singh: Puritan bohot.
Anshu singh: 2025 mein.
Anshu singh: Tovo data hum feijk karke dbi silica.
Krish NAik: Okay, DB matlap kum.
Anshu singh: karing.
Krish NAik: Generally, as a marketer bath come DB jo sub kud subcut kart. And I feel that to magar sequel ka normal bataro SQL doesn't support vector search.
Krish NAik: It means that you can multi-collection, multi-tenant, verify karke architecture palli bana podega.
Anshu singh: Tar mein das den ka umse Monday ko ex CSV file leuka das den ka data.
Anshu singh: quiz.
Krish NAik: Kusto chagi.
Anshu singh: aka.
Krish NAik: for Kari Kamet. It takes.
Anshu singh: Huh.
Krish NAik: it takes time. Like, even I have worked with DRDO, power times like that.
Krish NAik: About time, I see. It happens.
Krish NAik: Okay. Forum is also.
MS: push it.
Krish NAik: his number, just wait. I think host and panelist. So, Saurabhka number, I think you can see it from the chat.
Krish NAik: I'm sure.
Anshu singh: Yes, sir.
Krish NAik: Yes? Yes. Get his number.
Anshu singh: Yeah.
Anshu singh: Okay, sir, thank you. Monday Go Milte, sir.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, now, let's move to next. Who is next? You can let me know.
MS: Hey, hi, I had just a couple of queries, so I don't need.
Krish NAik: Okay, MS, MS, you start in the meantime. I'm sure you can stop sharing your screen. Naga, you are sharing, alright. Then, MS.
Naga: Oh.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes, go off.
Krish NAik: First of all, you go.
Naga: Yeah. So, also, I have this question. Any of the OCR options? So, as per the code, they're asking to use any of this, Tesseract, all this?
Krish NAik: Product.
Naga: I'm going to the document processor.
Naga: So, where do I… how do I switch it to the… I mean, currently, it seems like already it's using the docklink, right? As for this, like, document converter, docklink?
Naga: So…
Krish NAik: Yes, so are you asking me which line to change?
Naga: Yeah, where do I change exactly that?
Krish NAik: That will be inside your document converter. When you are doing the initialization of the document converter, there you have to do it.
Naga: Where, like, document processor and.
Krish NAik: Document converter, where you were doing the initialization of that, there you have to do it.
Naga: AmyFreshman.io?
Krish NAik: moment converter in that page only when you were doing the import and where you were doing the initialization there.
Naga: You mean to say in this one?
Krish NAik: line number…
Naga: 11.
Naga: The number 11, okay, document converter, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, here, you have to do changes. So, for that, you have to refer to the official documentation.
Naga: The… so this document converter,
Naga: So it has a O2.
Krish NAik: So you have to check this, and then based on that, you have to pass it.
Naga: So, I need to implement this service, or what?
Krish NAik: Yes, you have to do the implementation.
Krish NAik: In your case, if one OCR is not working, then you need to change the backend code, no?
Krish NAik: Because the default one is the Rapidos here. Now, if you want to do a custom implementation, you have to look into the documentation, and you have to do that implementation.
Naga: So, document converter, if I try to search…
Krish NAik: Document converter is in your import.
Naga: In the import, okay, okay. Okay, okay, documentation, okay, I see.
Krish NAik: Using this class, you need to do the implementation with your custom with your option.
Naga: Oh, God.
Naga: MS, I think you can go hurry.
MS: Yes. Hey, hi, Paul. So, one question I had, like, I ran the, the document ingestion and querying and all of that work. So, I see, like, in the response, I just downloaded it as a JSON, and I see query, answer, mode, sources, website. So, like, how do we control all the parameters that are coming in the response?
Krish NAik: It's generally through your Pytantic models, no, which I have, with models.py.
MS: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay. You decide the structure once, like, you can change the structure going forward, but initial structure, we always decide it from models.py. There, we fix it.
MS: Okay, okay, got it. Another thing, I had a more generic query. So, like, you know, while reading blocks and all, I often come across this statement that, like, these racks that we build for POCs, they are fine, but when we have to scale it to, say, hundreds or thousands of documents, that's where problem starts to come. So, anyway, we can get a flavor of that kind of problem statement. I know, like, generating embeddings for.
Krish NAik: How's and… like, now the question comes, what is the exact pain point?
Krish NAik: It can be with respect to document search, it can be… so you have to pick up that exact pinpoint, and you have to tell. It's not like… I cannot say every pinpoint I can get.
Krish NAik: Majorly, it is when one thing is… it can be with respect to, latency, for your search results from your vector TV. For that, a lot of other things, like,
Krish NAik: Your quantization with respect to binary things, which are other things which, in level of vector dividend needs to be taken care of.
Krish NAik: Where, your main prompt float, you will be changing it to quant or scalar-based quantizations, which will actually help you to reach in milliseconds the final result.
Krish NAik: So, now, instead, you have to tell me the exact problem, this is the problem, then I can tell you this is the solution.
MS: Got it, got it. And just one more, just a suggestion kind of thing. So, can you also give some assignments or something, like, to-do kind of thing, which can help us practice this?
Krish NAik: previously, once I have done but people… so, for example, when I say, like, you can raise a peer on top by main repo, always think in that way. Like, you think what is the functionality that you want to add on top of, like, project 2.
Krish NAik: Because if I directly say, do this task, rather than doing this task becomes pretty much hand-holding.
Krish NAik: Rather than you think about a functionality and start implementing on top of that particular project. I feel that is much better, rather than me giving a single assignment.
MS: Got it, got it, makes sense. Okay, thank you, thanks a lot.
Hari Kumar: Hi, Paul. My question.
Krish NAik: be honest.
Hari Kumar: more related to, the architecture diagrams, which you have showcased to the right. And also, it was a bit extensive, I mean, Project 2, did not borrow very much, but, I'm going through it. But Project 3, it's pretty much, clear. Project 3 is…
Krish NAik: chatting project to a lot of other things out there.
Hari Kumar: That is what they're talking about.
Hari Kumar: be tech, I mean, exhaustive for me, but yeah, I need to go through multiple files. However, my question is revolving around these architecture diagrams,
Hari Kumar: Right? How do you, in general, how… what is the way you prepare? And, what I see in my teams, right, we won't follow this kind of extensive architecture, and down the line, it becomes a problem.
Hari Kumar: How to visualize this kind of.
Krish NAik: Generally, generally, like, before the class, like, even I didn't create it, I created in the morning, I asked, GPT, so, like,
Krish NAik: for 3 of those response modes, like Standard, RAD, create me mermaid workflows in Markdown files that I have created, because those are mermaid codes which are being rendered in that. That is the only thing that I told, and then finally I told an entire, that project architecture document, create me in Markdown, same thing.
Krish NAik: Only, I think, 2-3 lines of things that I have added.
Hari Kumar: Okay, is it? Okay, so what is it, mermaid? I didn't get that.
Krish NAik: Mermaid. Mermaid is the type of that diagram.
Hari Kumar: Okay.
Krish NAik: mermaid.live, there is a proper website, and the code is there. So you can actually copy-paste that code, and you can execute that if you don't want to render it.
Krish NAik: So, for example, if I show you, this is desktop 3. No, in every file that I have, when I go inside my workflows, you have this CRAG one, okay? Now, this is actually a code. See, mermaid?
Krish NAik: So, this you can actually copy, okay, and you can paste it into that.
Hari Kumar: Ziplop.
Krish NAik: site of mermaid.live.
Krish NAik: So, here you have your mermaid.
Hari Kumar: You can see mermaid.lake.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you can see this piece of code from my other project also, this is coming here. I will paste it.
Krish NAik: Now, you will see the same code here.
Hari Kumar: No, got it. So, these MD files are generated based on the prompt from our codes, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, because, like, before that I have done, so I know the context was there.
Hari Kumar: We didn't.
Krish NAik: based on the context. Otherwise, you have to tell that, okay, from this file, this is the logic, analyze it, and based on that, build it.
Naga: But, Chris, you are doing the… sorry, ma'am.
Naga: Paul, sir, you're doing, directly there some preview, right?
Naga: Review of the mermaid.
Krish NAik: directly?
Naga: And .
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes, yes. Like, when I do the preview, because this is a Markdown file, no. So I have to re-open this Markdown file through your, like, extension. So automatically, if you are using Markdown, your mermaid gets automatically rendered.
Naga: Okay, so we have to install something from here? Extension?
Krish NAik: This one that I am using, this Markdown Preview Enhanced.
Naga: Oh, okay, I've done preview, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: That is the other way. Otherwise, manually, the code that I have shared in that, that also you can paste it in mermaid.live, then you can download, like, diagrams and other things. I think inside actions, you can get all those download options.
Naga: Welcome.
Hari Kumar: Hence why, yeah, it's clear not in the world.
jagapathi: Paul, can you hear me?
Krish NAik: Yes, I can hear. Mitesh, in the meantime, you, I think, Mitesh, you have done the implementation of that one. Changed the OCR backend?
Mitesh Shah: Yes, I had that.
Mitesh Shah: change it to AZOCR, and actually it is giving a better.
Krish NAik: Alright, just wait, and then just show it to others also. I think people might, stuck there. Okay, so show that implementation. Naga, stop sharing your screen.
Naga: Yes.
Krish NAik: Yeah, and Mitesh, you can start sharing and help out others in that case.
Krish NAik: Alright, now.
jagapathi: Paul, I have a little question.
Krish NAik: In Jagapati, you are sharing your screen, please let me know.
jagapathi: Yeah, yeah, I'm sharing my screen. You're looking at my screen, I believe.
jagapathi: Yeah, so… Yeah, it's done.
jagapathi: It is coming at index page, I'm talking about project 2-1, index.
Krish NAik: page. I could not get it.
jagapathi: an image here, right? A dot index is there.
jagapathi: Okay, let me log in.
Krish NAik: Dot index means, what is the exact thing that you are showing me right now in the screen?
jagapathi: I'm trying to… let me log into AWS. I think I just now logged in.
Krish NAik: Because I can see your code editor, whose screen I'm seeing, now I'm confused. Okay, I'm seeing into Mithe screen.
Krish NAik: Alright, you are logging into AWS in AWS? Alright, this is for Project 2.
jagapathi: Yeah, these were correct.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes.
jagapathi: Project time sorted, I got the… I just had to verify the queries. This is working for me.
Krish NAik: In Project 3, this should be an image, 3.12, when you actually open it. It should not be image index.
jagapathi: Yeah, that's what my question is, like, it is supposed to come as image, you know, the stag name. I'm not sure why is it getting per index.
jagapathi: this causing me error, and, like, I could not create the lambda function.
Krish NAik: Because…
jagapathi: wrong.
Krish NAik: It should be image by default, like, I…
Krish NAik: If there is some problem with respect to the image, well, generally, then we get this one. Just try to delete that image and try to, initialize your CI. Once. Let me see. Delete this, delete this one. Delete all the images from here.
jagapathi: I tried this ball, like…
Krish NAik: Every time image underscore index is only coming.
jagapathi: Yeah, correct.
jagapathi: So I think I'm making the same mistake recurring.
Krish NAik: Because then, in your GitHub actions, exactly, like, what is that?
Krish NAik: show me, like, I have to look into the GitHub action logs.
Krish NAik: Okay, before this, just wait. Mitesh, just, share your screen and tell that solution, because I think 4 to 5 people are looking that, then Jagaphatia will look into this one.
jagapathi: Sure, sure, no problem.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, quickly share your screen and just show them exactly which line code that you have changed.
Krish NAik: Noted.
Krish NAik: Document processor, alright. Inside that, PDF pipeline options, do OCR is equal to true.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this entire thing, you have done it.
Krish NAik: And you have created, this one.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: take this piece of code, okay, and paste it somewhere, like a GitHub guest, or in some place, so that others I can share it with.
Krish NAik: Anywhere, like, take that full class implementation or full file implementation, like, Ctrl-A, and create a GitHub guest, it is a public guest.
Krish NAik: Others can directly, I think, take that.
Mitesh Shah: I will, I will share it in Japan, I'm not sure.
Krish NAik: Just share it anywhere, like, then other code share.io, you can share it there also.
Krish NAik: Anyway.
Krish NAik: Then I can create a guest, okay, or drop me a mail, codeshare.io, I think, yes. Codeshare.
Krish NAik: Just hit enter.
Krish NAik: Here you will get it free. Share code now. Paste that entire file. Done.
Krish NAik: And keep it in view-only mode, see.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, people will edit it, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, only register, leave it for now, leave it now. Others, people, please, have a copy to this one. He has already shared this one.
Krish NAik: Refu, please.
Mitesh Shah: I think so if we want to just change it, this is the line where you're OTR.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think. That is the main, line, the easier, easier option. Okay, so people like Naga and others, please look into the course share, and based on that, please do update.
Krish NAik: For whoever is changing their OCR backend, please, check from…
Mitesh Shah: So, I had done a different route, so basically I'm using one very specific to text to SQL and…
Mitesh Shah: I have a very big database, now, 100 plus tables, plus…
Mitesh Shah: Wanted to check with you if you can help me with some, basic thing, which I have to set it up with context part of VANA.
Mitesh Shah: I'm not able to fine-tune VANA because it is killing me.
Mitesh Shah: Somewhere in terms of So, need your help, so shall I just drop an email and…
Mitesh Shah: Perfection is possible.
Krish NAik: Like, again, like, say, if you have 100 tables, if I'm taking, I'm not worried about the views right now.
Krish NAik: 100 tables, when you say, like, so, according to you, when you are trying to define that, schema context, that you'll be passing it to the LLM, like, what is the token size for that?
Mitesh Shah: It goes itself, like… Few tables would have one
Mitesh Shah: 50 plus, columns, I can reduce it, but the token size should typically go plus 30K miss.
Krish NAik: Because…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if it becomes 30K, Nitesh, okay, then, because 30K sending that same prompt again and again doesn't make meaning for me.
Krish NAik: I will move to prompt catching. I will use LLM which supports prompt catching. Every LLM doesn't support prompt catching, but I will actually move to prompt catching, because if I need to use that prompt again and again, that's fine.
Mitesh Shah: Got two, okay.
Krish NAik: Like, prompt catching is supported by Anthropic models, OpenAI models.
Mitesh Shah: Okay, I will look into this.
Krish NAik: Alright, yeah. Abhishek is asking, what is the best strategy to implement LLM ops with respect to AWS platform? I think I shared one guest in class, Abhishek, in that everything with respect to RAG
Krish NAik: Okay, because after project 3, this task, even I'll be giving… you can look into my guest.
Krish NAik: Okay, Abhishek, so I think,
Krish NAik: There, I shared to Rahul and others in class, where is that?
Krish NAik: My guest, create a new guest, guest, guest search.
Krish NAik: in Fry AWS or something like that on you guys.
Krish NAik: Just wait, from my activity also, I can see.
Krish NAik: Where can I get all my guit list?
Krish NAik: Indeed that it will…
Krish NAik: list of guests, anybody, like, I know, like, I created a guest quickly, but Gest, yes.
Krish NAik: Yeah, that's good.
Krish NAik: I've not done this listing, Discover guest.
Krish NAik: Yes, this AWS, Azure Ag, and RaviShek, okay? So you can check. This document is entirely for
Krish NAik: an AWS-based solution.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this was the best actually I was looking into.
Krish NAik: This is a full LLM Ops AWS-based platform with RAT-based, okay? So… Perfect. Now, next…
Krish NAik: Mmm, okay. Anybody else who want to… I think Santosh and Kodalu, sir, you have raised your hand.
Krish NAik: Well, like, whoever is raising their hand, please let me know in the chat.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, yeah, boy.
Krish NAik: when I…
Santosh Umargi: I just want to ask you, like, for, two to three years of experience now, what type of questions will come for these, RAG, RAG-based roles or Agent AI-based roles?
Krish NAik: Mmm, I think there was.
Santosh Umargi: Yes, this much detail is not required, no CRAC… Self-reflective, or just concept-wise?
Krish NAik: One or two years it is required, because, like, if somebody's doing that in the rack, these are common things.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because these are old papers, like, I cannot say these are, like, 2025 papers, these are old 2024 papers. So, yes, in the market, these things are famous.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, great.
Santosh Umargi: And you were about to show us something, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, like, Akariti… I forgot that name, Akariti… Mother Wallet.
Santosh Umargi: Jagapatis finish theirs.
Krish NAik: No, no, that is fine.
Krish NAik: coordinator, I have to look into projects. Any interview questions.
Krish NAik: This is a good repo, you can actually log into this repo.
Krish NAik: Let me share it into the chat.
Krish NAik: Chair, chair, chair, yes.
Krish NAik: I've added this one. This was the report that I was talking about.
Santosh Umargi: With the interview questions.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: This was very much trending, so, like, I'm not attack with the other one.
Krish NAik: Excellent.
Santosh Umargi: And, like, projects, what we did, no, like, this text to SQL, no? Can it be directly show, like, some twisting to the, real, like, real-world problem statement in our company, right?
Krish NAik: See, you can take… see, project 2 data I've taken, you can take more than 50 to 60% of the functionality.
Santosh Umargi: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I feel that, like, see, again, if you want to ask me, you can take this CRAG implementation and you can add it as a module there, which I feel…
Krish NAik: Yeah, every one needs the web search functionality added, okay?
Krish NAik: So, those things that, you need to… like, finally, when you are doing, like, you have to think, like, from one project to modules, project three modules, slowly, slowly, other projects also.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes, which can be plug-and-play? It means that some things you don't want to use according to your use case, and some things you feel that, yes, most of the times, that needs to be used. Now, those decisions, according to your use case, you need to take it.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, thank you, Baldwin.
Krish NAik: All right. Yes, I think, sir, you are presenting, please let me know, and Mohammad.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have everything going.
Krish NAik: Okay, huh?
Kodali Purna Chand: Can you… can you… can you hear me?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I can see. Alright, now tell me.
Kodali Purna Chand: Okay, okay, probably I'll make the query simple,
Kodali Purna Chand: Okay, I've uploaded a document, and everything is okay.
Kodali Purna Chand: So, I'm basically trying to do a query.
Kodali Purna Chand: I maintained enable hadith false, and enable re-ranking as false. So, this is working alright, I'm getting the response.
Kodali Purna Chand: The part which I wanted to clarify is, when I enable ID or enable re-ranking to true, the…
Kodali Purna Chand: The scoring goes beyond 1. How do I deal with that? Now receive, you can see the scoring is .65.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, that is fine. See, this particular score is based on IP, inner product.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm sorry?
Krish NAik: Now, this particular scoring is based on IP, inner product.
Kodali Purna Chand: Right.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is something like that, simply minus infinity to infinity.
Krish NAik: the one, better it is. Later on, if you want to do, you have to perform some type of normalization on top of that.
Kodali Purna Chand: So, just by changing this to true, it is going to 3 plus.
Krish NAik: Yes, because right now, again, for Heidi, 3 separate, statements that will be generated, okay, as far as the query, so that's why, yes, this will be. But again, if you are actually having something factual.
Krish NAik: Truth Lookout. In that.
Kodali Purna Chand: It's right.
Krish NAik: ID doesn't help so much.
Kodali Purna Chand: Oh, okay.
Kodali Purna Chand: So I was only concerned as to why it's coming up so high.
Kodali Purna Chand: Because it's a type of query transformation only.
Krish NAik: Not… in some cases, it can be helpful. So in… like, when you feel that the query is not…
Krish NAik: The query is very small.
Krish NAik: Okay, now that… there, you need more details to be attached. In those cases, I feel that it's better.
Kodali Purna Chand: Okay.
Kodali Purna Chand: Okay, so there's no… there's no concern if… I'll show you this so that you have a view of…
Kodali Purna Chand: what is the scoring that is coming up, and I'm changing those two through…
Krish NAik: If your main query is changed, then automatically the score will be impacted.
Kodali Purna Chand: The query is the same, but I've just changed that,
Kodali Purna Chand: Heidi to be true, and, re-ranking to be true.
Krish NAik: Because after re-ranking, I think, that main score, that's getting changed.
Krish NAik: Because the index of your main document, that will also be changed.
Kodali Purna Chand: Hmm… Okay, that's what… I was not sure if this is something that I'm doing wrong, or is this.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, this is correct. That's why, generally, like, re-ranking takes more time. Use any one of them, and always after re-ranking, your scores will be impacted. Why? Because the scoring mechanism, there is different, and direct standard track is different.
Krish NAik: In standard drag, it's pretty much the cosine similarity.
Kodali Purna Chand: Okay.
Kodali Purna Chand: Okay, thank you.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think, others, like Mohammad, Mantage, both of you.
Mantaaj: Hey, Paul, I hope you can hear me.
Krish NAik: Yes, I can.
Mantaaj: Yeah.
Mantaaj: Paul, just one quick question,
Mantaaj: I was just going through this…
Mantaaj: document underscore parser.py file, right? So where, in the constructor, we have…
Mantaaj: define this document converter and hybrid chunkers, right? So, this document converter is a…
Mantaaj: class, I'm a little… have we… are we going through… going through this class, or method, or it's… we have already covered it, I'm…
Krish NAik: We have already covered it during Dockling class. In Dockling, I took a dedicated class
Krish NAik: One lecture showing doc links.
Krish NAik: In that class, we have discussed docklings.
Mantaaj: Okay, we have gone through multiple documents, the parsing, different type of parsing mechanism, so this… this was one of the classes over there.
Krish NAik: The first, I think, the first class of document parts only I discussed, DocLink, then I discussed Unstructured, and then LamaPars. So, in that docklink notebook, you can check, because the reference, you can get it from there.
Mantaaj: Okay, okay, I will check that bar. Okay, thanks.
Krish NAik: Next…
Krish NAik: Anybody next, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Mantaja, I will lower your hand right now, take it home. Muhammad, I have asked you to unmute, no? I think you can speak.
Krish NAik: But I cannot hear you.
Krish NAik: If there is some type of audio issue, please… Check from your end.
Krish NAik: Because I cannot hear.
Krish NAik: Because you can write it in the chat, or if you want to do any… Good.
Krish NAik: Yes, Jagopathy.
Naga: Can I ask a question?
Krish NAik: ESTIC.
Naga: So this, I changed the code and, trying to upload, I mean, another document.
Naga: But, in this Docker, do I see something happening, like,
Naga: How do I know, like, if it's taking the… new, embeddings.
Krish NAik: Is this running?
Naga: Yeah, it's running.
Naga: Oh, it's not Ryan?
Naga: See? Green is running high.
Krish NAik: Green means click on containers, don't look into images.
Naga: But.
Krish NAik: Containers tell you that idea.
Naga: Well, and I don't.
Krish NAik: Here, it's telling. Now you can actually go and check into that,
Krish NAik: EY. Now, I know that your container is running, it means that, yes, your quadrant is running.
Naga: Product is running, okay. Now, if I go back to my character rack, I uploaded one huge document after the code change.
Naga: It's continuously just sitting on this phone.
Krish NAik: So, from your, response in your terminal, what is the data you are getting?
Naga: No error, just, like, continuously keep loading, without any error.
Krish NAik: Because first time, it should take.
Krish NAik: Like, probably 1 minute or 2 minutes, but after that, it should not take.
Mohammad(MJ): Yeah.
Naga: No, more than 5 minutes, like, 5 minutes it's running. The same symptom was there, I mean, error-wise.
Krish NAik: If there is no error, like…
Krish NAik: Because at least I need some error.
Mohammad(MJ): Actually showing validation error on the screen, if you go back to the docs.
Naga: Docs? This one?
Mohammad(MJ): Yeah.
Mohammad(MJ): Go back to the page, you load up your, document. It says on the bottom, validation error. If you scroll down.
Mohammad(MJ): There we go. Okay, hold on, go up.
Naga: Whoa.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, it's loading only, no? There is no… Identity error is not coming.
Naga: I loaded since, like, 5 minutes ago, so it is continuously doing, but I mean, my intention was to check if the…
Naga: Anywhere its embeddings are getting created, or the vector DVR, at least I want to see the progress, that's what I'm saying.
Krish NAik: So that, you can check from your local host, you can open your UI, quadrant UI, and if you want to have a check that whether the collection got created or not.
Naga: Marativa is here, so, collections, okay.
Krish NAik: Absolutely.
Naga: Just slip of mine.
Krish NAik: This got created.
Naga: So, two segment and one shard.
Naga: What?
Krish NAik: 0 points means zero points means there are no chumps. Points are your chums.
Naga: Okay, points are… so nothing came in, right, in this?
Krish NAik: So, work on that, document processing part, because generally the issue will be from Docklink side.
Krish NAik: Change your backend?
Krish NAik: And then test.
Naga: That is the… Welcome.
Naga: Document processor, I just changed the code to the… Toward the…
Naga: Our guy has given the code, not that one. The Mitesh.
Naga: So, I disabled the rapid OCR, and I'm taking the hybrid chunker.
Naga: This is a code he's given.
Krish NAik: Right, fine, this is the code. Now you have to, based on that AZOCR installation in your system, that should also be available.
Naga: OCR installation, yeah.
Naga: Which installation?
Krish NAik: What is EZOCR? If you are using EasyOCR, so what is the meaning of that?
Naga: EZOCR is a… is a package, like, yes.
Krish NAik: So, that particular package… Is it available in your system?
Naga: And I don't do so.
Naga: I didn't…
Krish NAik: You need to take care of that, so docklink with EasyOCR, according to the official documentation, you need to do that. Yes, just provide you the code, but other packages, you need to do the installation from your end.
Naga: Okay, okay, the people install this, easy, easy, okay, fine.
VRAJ PATEL: Yes, sir. Can you hear me?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I can.
VRAJ PATEL: So, sir, I have a question regarding one project currently I'm working on.
VRAJ PATEL: Where I have multiple types of documents, in terms of PDF, docs, some audio files.
VRAJ PATEL: So, I want to create a search engine on top of that, where I can do
VRAJ PATEL: Means find us, search based on keyword-based, or…
Krish NAik: Nope.
VRAJ PATEL: Cementing the booth.
VRAJ PATEL: So, currently, I created one POC, where I'm using the Quadrant as a vector database, and put the sparse net, sparse vectors and, lens vectors both in the Quadrant vector database.
VRAJ PATEL: And now I want to create such that if I want to create, if I want to retrieve, based on only, sparse vectors, then also it can be done. And if I want to do some semantic-based search, then also it can be possible. So, is there possible in the quadrant vector database?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes, yes, in quadrant, say, Viraj, I think this class… just give me time, tomorrow I will show you that.
Krish NAik: Because I think BM25 implementation is not there. I will add that implementation, and I will show you. Separately, you can do separate searches. One search for hybrid, and one such for sparse-specific only.
VRAJ PATEL: Okay.
Mohammad(MJ): Hey, can you hear me, Paul?
Krish NAik: Yes, Mahata.
Mohammad(MJ): Okay, so, my question, actually, in regards to the class we've been taking, I know it's been almost… it's going to be 4 months?
Mohammad(MJ): That's gonna go up to another couple months or month and a half. So if we master all those concepts that you gave to us, appreciate all the details you gave.
Mohammad(MJ): Is it gonna be really a big jump on the AI engineer?
Krish NAik: not see.
Mohammad(MJ): Cool.
Krish NAik: AI engine… not only AI, AI engineering is a very generic track. In Gen AI, in Gen AI engineers, like, one works with LLM, one with RAG, and the other one is, like, LLM ops with RAG.
Mohammad(MJ): Okay. Okay. And the fourth one right now, for the past one year, the other one is agents. Now, we'll say people say agents, so that.
Krish NAik: Agents are a combination of, like, LLM, rather than through tool usage that you mainly do.
Krish NAik: Now, majorly, like, through this course, one track, which is the RAC, like, every organization has a 10-15% requirement of RAT.
Krish NAik: Whereas LLM is much lower.
Krish NAik: I feel. Now, and agents is the third one which is right now tendering more than rack, because the same thing, once I start teaching agents, I can show you that the same thing that we can do, the same implementation of CRAC, SRAC, whatever the rack that I've implemented. The only feature will be, you'll be having that statefulness.
Krish NAik: like, state management will be available through agent-based implementation, that is. Now, the same thing that I have done, you can think about, I can wrap it within a function, make it as a tool call, okay, and your agent can access the same things.
Krish NAik: So, it's a branch of Gen AI, very specifically, because AI engineer, when you say, the expectations from AI engineer are, like, you should have good knowledge of deep learning also, that machine learning, all those things, but for a generic Gen AI engineer.
Krish NAik: Then, that stack is not, at least, like, few things like deep learning and statistics, that can be ignored, at least, to a certain extent.
Mohammad(MJ): Right, because I'll be honest with you, Paul, I'm trying to determine the next thing for me, like.
Mohammad(MJ): Like, yes, I'm gonna try to do my best to master as much as possible in the concept and the RAG that you teach, but in the next thing, I know, sometimes when you go over some
Mohammad(MJ): concept, like, my background actually didn't come from data science or any of that stuff. I'm more like a full-stack developer and back-end, front-end, some of the DevOps, more like a senior software engineer. So, I'm looking… the next step is, do I need to get deeper, really, on…
Mohammad(MJ): The concept of the data science, the transformers, that the stuff you were telling us before, you guys need to know about all these when you start talking about, like, is it really worth to go back to the deep, to the basic, then start focusing back on the… the trending, or just…
Mohammad(MJ): Focus just on the foundation, important ones.
Krish NAik: Transformers is just, like, the foundation. It means that.
Naga: In an interview, in a technical interview, if you go.
Krish NAik: anybody can ask you a question related to that. It doesn't matter senior. That's why I feel that from Transformers, before Transformers, you can skip things.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, classic and NLP stuff, but at least the deep learning NLP, starting from transformers, everything is important. Now, when I say everything is important, it means that the poor architectures, like, you should have a good knowledge of GPT and board.
Krish NAik: Sure. Which is encoder-based and decoder-based. Once you have those basics.
Krish NAik: Then you can directly jump into Gen AI.
Mohammad(MJ): Okay, that makes me feel better, because…
Krish NAik: Hmm. Like…
Mohammad(MJ): I don't know if anyone cared to know about EDA, like, do I need to go back and EDA? EDA, now you can generate it through AI, and can do it all for you.
Krish NAik: You can… see, that's why, when you're actually building a product.
Krish NAik: These things matter from scratch. Okay, like, your own product, then you actually think about, to a certain research, to convert that research into an implementation, we take steps necessary.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, open source implementations are there.
Krish NAik: But at least I feel that when, if you are leading a team, as you already have done that, you have the knowledge of ops and other things, you should focus on a little bit of data engineering side also, because exactly how to handle data at scale in production, it's important.
Krish NAik: From your… if you have not worked, at least you should look into that part.
Krish NAik: If you have that, that is the first thing. Like, my common question, what is the velocity of the data?
Krish NAik: Okay, like, in real time, then I understand that whether he's going for a streaming-based solution or a batch-based solution. So, pretty common questions are there for… but yes, a little bit about that particular thing also, explore from data engineering perspective.
Mohammad(MJ): Okay, appreciate that, Paul. Thank you very much.
Krish NAik: Josephine is asking, is BGM3 for sparse and tense and BMI for keybase?
Krish NAik: BMI, when you say BMI, for, like, I prefer BGM3, yes, you can do that, sparse, dense, and multi-vector. That is also possible.
Krish NAik: Okay, and BMI, I could not get this, BMI.
Krish NAik: BP, I know BMI, what are you referring to, that BMI part? Josephine, quickly tell me in the chat.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Nope.
VRAJ PATEL: Sir, I have one more question as well.
Krish NAik: Leon Mirage.
VRAJ PATEL: And we are going to search on the web store database, as I have a very used dataset, around 80 to 90K chunks.
VRAJ PATEL: Right? So…
VRAJ PATEL: I want to retrieve the chunks in less than 1 or 2 seconds, based on my query. So…
Krish NAik: One or two… yes, you can do. See, a few things that need to be done. First of all, your data type that needs to be changed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… implement HNSW.
Krish NAik: few things that can be done. If you want, I will just share one resource with you.
Krish NAik: Just wait, where is that, one?
Krish NAik: Because… just wait, I think it's in my WhatsApp, or what.
Krish NAik: Somewhere that document was there, just with… if I can get the link quickly.
Krish NAik: Blink, link… what's… what's up, what's up?
Krish NAik: Alright, I'm sharing this link, just wait, let me copy it from my iPhone, copy link.
Krish NAik: Okay, just let me see. This was a good block.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, that's not listening.
Krish NAik: Copying from my phone, I think, yes, now I can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, 200 millisecond, yeah, this is the document.
Krish NAik: You can use any type of wall loader, and you can bypass this one, but this is the one.
Krish NAik: Sure, sure, thanks so much.
Krish NAik: Like, all those are, like, binary scale-level activation. The same thing you can get in quadrant, as well as in…
Krish NAik: The list. I have majorly done those two implementations, but, yes, these two are really good ones.
Krish NAik: Where is the chat window? Yes, I have pasted it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally the data type and the same thing you can, check from quadrant.
Krish NAik: H and SW.
Krish NAik: So these two are the main ones.
Krish NAik: One is HNSW implementation that you have to do, the other one is, with respect to quantization.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Quanti enable quantization, yeah, this is the…
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, with respect to quadrant, it's written, but this feature is available majorly everywhere, where you have to change, and it actually, like, reduces the size also.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that your main,
Krish NAik: Vector TV size also get, reduced, so this is a really good one, I feel. So, enable quantization. Here, type in date everywhere. So, I'm sharing this also, you can check. Ziliz also has very similar articles.
Krish NAik: But these need to be taken care of.
VRAJ PATEL: Thank you.
Krish NAik: Alright, so measly, I think everybody's done. Now, yes, Jagavati. So, look, just show me the…
Krish NAik: Logs for that one.
Krish NAik: GitHub action logs.
Krish NAik: Get our action laws, just showing it itself.
Krish NAik: We have action logs, yes.
Krish NAik: What is the size of this image that you have in your local?
Krish NAik: 1.73 GB.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Because of that full image is not coming, because of that… that…
Krish NAik: Artifact image index type, it's coming.
Naga: Not giving you any error, but I installed that package also, Paul.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Naga: But still, it's… Yeah, senior,
Naga: Next.
Naga: in.com.
Naga: Not at all.
Naga: Oh, okay, what is your error?
Krish NAik: step, Jagapati, can you, like, do it manually? Because I think I have shared a script of building the base image.
Krish NAik: And then pushing it manually.
Krish NAik: to this one.
Krish NAik: Go to the repo.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, here it's not written. Newdeploy.md won't get written.
Krish NAik: Go to the main, file, yes. This auto-build… Auto-built, go below. Auto-built.
Krish NAik: Me, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, yes.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the first step, like, go on top, top, top, top, top.
Krish NAik: How it works, this, base image detection, alright? I think I've shared that file, build hyphen base imageimage.sh.
Krish NAik: You need to use that file to build the base image, first of all.
Krish NAik: Build a base image in your root directory.
Krish NAik: Go to that build hyphen base. No, no, look into the files. Left-hand side, yes, there is a build base, which, yes, that is the script.
Krish NAik: I want you to create this image manually, change your AWS account ID and other things, okay, according to your own configuration, then create it and then manually push it.
Krish NAik: Yes, quickly tell me on that one, because I want, you to manually create the image, and let's see, like, what is the main issue.
Krish NAik: Because the issue needs to be debugged from that level.
Krish NAik: And Naga, in your case, like, till now, there is no response or any error specific to that?
Naga: You know, yeah, like, here I'm not getting… in quadrant, I'm not getting an error,
Naga: Here, it's… Continuously waiting, it's a very small document, just an iPad.
Naga: No error. There are also no error, and… I installed that package also, that easy OCR package also got installed.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Naga: And then I… Spin up other… Why it's waiting, I mean…
Naga: No, the waiting time is really bad.
Naga: No error. Maybe it's, system is overloaded because of 100% CPU, maybe?
Krish NAik: I don't think, instead of just a single PDF, so it should not be…
Krish NAik: Stressing the system so much at a time.
Naga: I don't know what is the problem, but earlier I was able to do this one, but not.
Naga: Waking along, still, but straight.
Krish NAik: This is a shell script, so probably you need to execute this from… I think Gita Bash, or…
Krish NAik: Like, if you have that Ubuntu, I think, what do you call it, WSN.
Krish NAik: in Windows.
Naga: Goodbye, Philip.
Krish NAik: Generally, like, Git Vash is required, or WSL.
Naga: WSF?
Krish NAik: No, no, not for you, I'm telling for Jagavati.
Naga: Autism.
Krish NAik: Yes, dot slash and then give the name to that file, but update the account ID and all those things.
Krish NAik: Before executing, please update the account ID in that script. I have… that is my account ID.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have done those updates, AP South 1, you can proceed ahead then, if you feel.
Krish NAik: Okay, now after this step, what is the next step that you will be doing? Jagaparti? So, you have to manually, first of all, log into AWS ECR, and then push… okay, this, you can see, log in to Amazon. Before that, have you deleted everything?
Krish NAik: Okay, build ACR repositories, okay, check that. I think, you have done the build previously because of that.
Krish NAik: Check, check, check, check.
Krish NAik: AWS, check AWS. And this should be updated, I think.
Krish NAik: Image and image came, I can see, but 0 and 0. Delete all these things once.
Krish NAik: Select or delete.
Krish NAik: Because, again, if something is missing from the image, delete it.
Krish NAik: Okay, go back.
Krish NAik: Okay, right here, like, Docker images.
Krish NAik: Check, because the images got built, so…
Krish NAik: Excellent lambda… Okay, this is a 3.12 tag.
Krish NAik: Alright. From that script, copy the command. In the script, the command is there. I think,
Krish NAik: Because manually, you have to tag, and we have to do that update.
Krish NAik: So, this is fine. Build, you have done, platform, that… docker lambda.dev.
Krish NAik: Okay… In your case, login was successful. After logging docker push.
Krish NAik: Full image URI. So… Full image URI, check the variable, what I've defined, full image URI on top.
Krish NAik: Yes, that variable in top water deliver.
Krish NAik: Check the script on top, okay, now this is ECR, ECR, image style, all those push. Actually, this is the script which will actually do the push.
Krish NAik: Execute the script once more, literally.
Krish NAik: Every time image tag is coming only, or, that part. Just same command, executed once again.
Krish NAik: Because these things quickly, too, will be done.
Krish NAik: You can see error, resolve.
Krish NAik: This is some internet issue, like TLS handshake that came this time.
Krish NAik: Let me check on this one, because I feel that this is some…
Krish NAik: Because locally, previously, the image was built.
Krish NAik: Please do a refresh from here. That was 18 hours ago, the last refresh, in your Docker.
Krish NAik: Last refresher there, no, huh? Refresh.
Krish NAik: Created 12 hours ago.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Let's slow down.
Krish NAik: The push, what happened?
Krish NAik: Told me that part.
Krish NAik: With respect to the push from your terminal, what is the log that you are getting?
jagapathi: Paul, did I logged out, or what in between?
Krish NAik: Oh, this screen sharing stop, it looks like.
Krish NAik: And Aya, in your, part, I can see till now, like, rapid OCR is being mentioned.
Naga: Yeah, it's mentioned that, but four changes already done.
Krish NAik: Then you have to be sure that you're speaking of the correct one.
Krish NAik: Create a test script and check the implementation is working or not.
Naga: Muhammad.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, from your terminal, because if the push is done.
Krish NAik: Because here it's telling 1.73 GB.
Krish NAik: Content size 433. Probably after the upload, it will be compressed.
Krish NAik: But this 3.12, it should be image, not image and text. Like, I feel there is some issue with respect to the image, that's why.
jagapathi: Yeah, it is nothing here.
Krish NAik: No, no, there is actually nothing with respect to this that you could get here. Because even I have deleted my ECR and that account.
Krish NAik: That is the main thing. I have to… Will you write Ritel?
Krish NAik: Do the build.
Krish NAik: Just wait once.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because even I forgot what is the name and other stuff.
Krish NAik: Let me try from my side.
Krish NAik: I've not done it for a long time.
Krish NAik: Increase?
Krish NAik: Hmm, this is still superfood.
Krish NAik: and bones.
jagapathi: I remember that day, somebody got the same issue, somebody got resolved later.
Krish NAik: Let me close this application.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because I deleted mine, that one, I think.
Krish NAik: First of all, I have to create the ECR report.
Krish NAik: Mmm, let him get the command.
Krish NAik: Alright, the first step is done. Now, moving back to…
Krish NAik: The next one, building the image.
Krish NAik: Good.
Krish NAik: Once the upload is done, then I will tell you.
Krish NAik: I hope you can see my screen, Javuti.
jagapathi: Oh, yes, Berlin.
Krish NAik: That's right, this is coming in age only.
jagapathi: Okay.
Krish NAik: That's why I tested it right now, manually. Manually, also, it's working.
Krish NAik: Because this is the same script, everything is same.
jagapathi: Is it 3.12? The Python motion, or…
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, tag 3.12 only, no?
Krish NAik: It's the same script, it's not like I'm using a different script. This is the same script that I've shared, that only I tested with a manual build.
jagapathi: Okay.
jagapathi: Let me try it in different repo, and try to build emissions.
Krish NAik: Okay, try that, and then let me know.
jagapathi: Yeah, sure.
Krish NAik: I'll keep it closer.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, then I'll be concluding the session. Okay, let's, discuss the code tomorrow, and I think I'll be adding that, BAM25 with hybrid rack routes.
Krish NAik: Okay? Two or three routes very specific to hybrid track only.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so a little bit, update that I'll be doing with respect to the application. The rest will be pretty much the same.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so let's… Concluded. Okay, and let's meet tomorrow and continue the discussion.
Krish NAik: Bye-bye, everyone, thanks for joining.
jagapathi: Thank you, Paul. Thank you, Paul. Thank you, Paul. Thank you both.